<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <!--The following translations were generated by https://www.deepl.com/-->
  <!-- EN: dogs -->
  <Dog.label>Hunde</Dog.label>
  <!-- EN: The dog (Canis familiaris when considered a distinct species or Canis lupus familiaris when considered a subspecies of the wolf) is a member of the genus Canis (canines), which forms part of the wolf-like canids, and is the most widely abundant terrestrial carnivore. The dog and the extant gray wolf are sister taxa as modern wolves are not closely related to the wolves that were first domesticated, which implies that the direct ancestor of the dog is extinct. The dog was the first species to be domesticated, and has been selectively bred over millennia for various behaviors, sensory capabilities, and physical attributes. -->
  <Dog.description>Der Hund (Canis familiaris, wenn er als eigenständige Art betrachtet wird, oder Canis lupus familiaris, wenn er als Unterart des Wolfes betrachtet wird) ist ein Mitglied der Gattung Canis (Eckzähne), die zu den wolfsähnlichen Caniden gehört, und ist das am weitesten verbreitete Landraubtier. Der Hund und der heutige graue Wolf sind Schwestertaxa, da moderne Wölfe nicht eng mit den Wölfen verwandt sind, die zuerst domestiziert wurden, was bedeutet, dass der direkte Vorfahre des Hundes ausgestorben ist. Der Hund war die erste domestizierte Tierart und wurde über Jahrtausende hinweg selektiv auf verschiedene Verhaltensweisen, sensorische Fähigkeiten und körperliche Merkmale gezüchtet.</Dog.description>
  <!-- EN: foxes -->
  <Fox.label>Füchse</Fox.label>
  <!-- EN: Vulpes is a genus of the Caninae. The members of this genus are colloquially referred to as true foxes, meaning they form a proper clade. The word "fox" occurs on the common names of species. True foxes are distinguished from members of the genus Canis, such as domesticated dogs, wolves, jackals and coyotes, by their smaller size (5–11 kg) and flatter skull. They have black, triangular markings between their eyes and nose, and the tip of their tail is often a different color from the rest of their pelt. The typical lifespan for this genus is between two and four years, but can reach up to a decade. -->
  <Fox.description>Vulpes ist eine Gattung der Caninae. Die Mitglieder dieser Gattung werden umgangssprachlich als echte Füchse bezeichnet, was bedeutet, dass sie eine eigene Gattung bilden. Das Wort "Fuchs" kommt in den gemeinsamen Namen der Arten vor. Echte Füchse unterscheiden sich von den Mitgliedern der Gattung Canis, wie Haushunden, Wölfen, Schakalen und Kojoten, durch ihre geringere Größe (5-11 kg) und ihren flacheren Schädel. Sie haben schwarze, dreieckige Markierungen zwischen Augen und Nase, und die Schwanzspitze hat oft eine andere Farbe als der Rest des Fells. Die typische Lebenserwartung dieser Gattung liegt zwischen zwei und vier Jahren, kann aber auch bis zu einem Jahrzehnt betragen.</Fox.description>
  <!-- EN: hyenas -->
  <Hyena.label>Hyänen</Hyena.label>
  <!-- EN: Hyenas, or hyaenas (from Ancient Greek ὕαινα, hýaina), are feliform carnivoran mammals of the family Hyaenidae. With only four extant species (in three genera), it is the fifth-smallest biological family in the Carnivora and one of the smallest in the class Mammalia. Despite their low diversity, hyenas are unique and vital components of most African ecosystems. -->
  <Hyena.description>Hyänen oder Hyaenas (von altgriechisch ὕαινα, hýaina) sind feliforme, fleischfressende Säugetiere aus der Familie der Hyaenidae. Mit nur vier existierenden Arten (in drei Gattungen) ist sie die fünftkleinste biologische Familie innerhalb der Carnivora und eine der kleinsten innerhalb der Klasse der Säugetiere. Trotz ihrer geringen Vielfalt sind Hyänen einzigartige und wichtige Bestandteile der meisten afrikanischen Ökosysteme.</Hyena.description>
  <!-- EN: tanukis -->
  <Tanuki.label>tanukis</Tanuki.label>
  <!-- EN: The Japanese raccoon dog (Nyctereutes procyonoides viverrinus), also known as the tanuki (Japanese: タヌキ or 狸; pronounced [taꜜnɯki]), is a subspecies of the Asian raccoon dog. Researchers have suggested that they be considered a separate species, N. viverrinus, or that raccoon dogs of Japan could be further divisible into separate subspecies as N. p. procyonoides (hondo-tanuki, ホンドタヌキ, 本土狸) and N. p. albus (ezo-tanuki, エゾタヌキ, 蝦夷狸), but both views are controversial. -->
  <Tanuki.description>Der japanische Marderhund (Nyctereutes procyonoides viverrinus), auch bekannt als Marderhund (japanisch: タヌキ oder 狸</Tanuki.description>
  <!-- EN: wargs -->
  <Warg.label>wargs</Warg.label>
  <!-- EN: The dire wolf (Canis dirus, "fearsome dog") is an extinct species of the genus Canis. It is one of the most famous prehistoric carnivores in North America, along with its extinct competitor, the sabre-toothed cat Smilodon fatalis. The dire wolf lived in the Americas during the Late Pleistocene and Early Holocene epochs (125,000–9,500 years ago). The species was named in 1858, four years after the first specimen had been found. Two subspecies are recognized: Canis dirus guildayi and Canis dirus dirus. The dire wolf probably evolved from Armbruster's wolf (Canis armbrusteri) in North America. The largest collection of its fossils has been obtained from the Rancho La Brea Tar Pits in Los Angeles. -->
  <Warg.description>Der Schattenwolf (Canis dirus, "furchterregender Hund") ist eine ausgestorbene Art der Gattung Canis. Er ist eines der bekanntesten prähistorischen Raubtiere Nordamerikas, zusammen mit seinem ausgestorbenen Konkurrenten, der Säbelzahnkatze Smilodon fatalis. Der Schattenwolf lebte in Amerika während des späten Pleistozäns und frühen Holozäns (vor 125.000-9.500 Jahren). Die Art wurde 1858 benannt, vier Jahre nachdem das erste Exemplar gefunden worden war. Es werden zwei Unterarten anerkannt: Canis dirus guildayi und Canis dirus dirus. Der Schattenwolf hat sich wahrscheinlich aus dem Armbruster-Wolf (Canis armbrusteri) in Nordamerika entwickelt. Die größte Sammlung seiner Fossilien wurde in den Rancho La Brea Tar Pits in Los Angeles gefunden.</Warg.description>
  <!-- EN: wolves -->
  <Wolf.label>Wölfe</Wolf.label>
  <!-- EN: The wolf (Canis lupus), also known as the "gray wolf" or "grey wolf", is a large canine native to Eurasia and North America. It is the largest extant member of Canidae, males averaging 40 kg (88 lb) and females 37 kg (82 lb). On average, wolves measure 105–160 cm (41–63 in) in length and 80–85 cm (31–33 in) at shoulder height. The wolf is also distinguished from other Canis species by its less pointed ears and muzzle, as well as a shorter torso and a longer tail. The wolf is nonetheless related closely enough to smaller Canis species, such as the coyote and the golden jackal, to produce fertile hybrids with them. The banded fur of a wolf is usually mottled white, brown, gray, and black. Up to 38 subspecies of wolf have been recognized including the domestic dog. -->
  <Wolf.description>Der Wolf (Canis lupus), auch bekannt als "grauer Wolf" oder "grauer Wolf", ist ein großer, in Eurasien und Nordamerika beheimateter Hund. Er ist das größte lebende Mitglied der Canidae, wobei männliche Tiere im Durchschnitt 40 kg und weibliche Tiere 37 kg wiegen. Im Durchschnitt messen Wölfe 105-160 cm in der Länge und 80-85 cm in der Schulterhöhe. Der Wolf unterscheidet sich von anderen Canis-Arten auch durch seine weniger spitzen Ohren und seine Schnauze sowie durch einen kürzeren Rumpf und einen längeren Schwanz. Der Wolf ist jedoch eng genug mit kleineren Canis-Arten wie dem Kojoten und dem Goldschakal verwandt, um fruchtbare Hybride mit ihnen zu erzeugen. Das gebänderte Fell der Wölfe ist in der Regel weiß, braun, grau und schwarz gefleckt. Es wurden bis zu 38 Unterarten des Wolfs anerkannt, darunter auch der Haushund.</Wolf.description>
</LanguageData>
