<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <!--The following translations were generated by https://www.deepl.com/-->
  <!-- EN: antelopes -->
  <Antelope.label>Antilopen</Antelope.label>
  <!-- EN: The term antelope is used to refer to many species of even-toed ruminant indigenous to various regions in Africa and Eurasia. Antelope comprise a wastebasket taxon (miscellaneous group) within the family Bovidae, encompassing all Old World ruminants that are not bovines, sheep, or goats. A group of antelope is called a herd. Unlike deer antlers, which are shed and grown annually, antelope horns grow continuously. -->
  <Antelope.description>Der Begriff Antilope wird verwendet, um viele Arten von Wiederkäuern mit glatten Zehen zu bezeichnen, die in verschiedenen Regionen Afrikas und Eurasiens heimisch sind. Antilopen bilden ein Abfallkorb-Taxon (diverse Gruppe) innerhalb der Familie Bovidae, die alle Wiederkäuer der Alten Welt umfasst, die keine Rinder, Schafe oder Ziegen sind. Eine Gruppe von Antilopen wird als Herde bezeichnet. Im Gegensatz zu Hirschgeweihen, die jährlich abgeworfen werden und wachsen, wachsen Antilopenhörner kontinuierlich.</Antelope.description>
  <!-- EN: armadillos -->
  <Armadillo.label>Gürteltiere</Armadillo.label>
  <!-- EN: Armadillos (meaning "little armored ones" in Spanish) are New World placental mammals in the order Cingulata. The Chlamyphoridae and Dasypodidae are the only surviving families in the order, which is part of the superorder Xenarthra, along with the anteaters and sloths. Nine extinct genera and 21 extant species of armadillo have been described, some of which are distinguished by the number of bands on their armor. All species are native to the Americas, where they inhabit a variety of different environments. -->
  <Armadillo.description>Gürteltiere (spanisch für "kleine Gepanzerte") sind Säugetiere aus der Neuen Welt, die zur Ordnung der Cingulata gehören. Die Chlamyphoridae und Dasypodidae sind die einzigen überlebenden Familien in dieser Ordnung, die zusammen mit den Ameisenbären und Faultieren zur Überordnung Xenarthra gehört. Es wurden neun ausgestorbene Gattungen und 21 lebende Gürteltierarten beschrieben, von denen sich einige durch die Anzahl der Bänder auf ihrem Panzer unterscheiden. Alle Arten sind in Amerika beheimatet, wo sie eine Vielzahl unterschiedlicher Lebensräume bewohnen.</Armadillo.description>
  <!-- EN: badgers -->
  <Badger.label>Dachse</Badger.label>
  <!-- EN: Badgers are short-legged omnivores mostly in the family Mustelidae (which also includes the otters, polecats, weasels, and ferrets), but also with two species called "badgers" in the related family Mephitidae (which also includes the skunks). Badgers are a polyphyletic grouping, and are not a natural taxonomic grouping: badgers are united by their squat bodies, adapted for fossorial activity. All belong to the caniform suborder of carnivoran mammals. -->
  <Badger.description>Dachse sind kurzbeinige Allesfresser, die hauptsächlich zur Familie der Mustelidae gehören (zu der auch Otter, Iltisse, Wiesel und Frettchen gehören), aber auch zwei als "Dachse" bezeichnete Arten in der verwandten Familie Mephitidae (zu der auch die Stinktiere gehören). Bei den Dachsen handelt es sich um eine polyphyletische Gruppierung, die keine natürliche taxonomische Gruppierung darstellt: Die Dachse sind durch ihren gedrungenen Körper, der an die Fossilität angepasst ist, miteinander verbunden. Alle gehören zur Unterordnung der fleischfressenden Säugetiere, den Caniformes.</Badger.description>
  <!-- EN: bears -->
  <Bear.label>Bären</Bear.label>
  <!-- EN: Ursus is a genus in the family Ursidae (bears) that includes the widely distributed brown bear, the polar bear, the American black bear, and the Asian black bear. The name is derived from the Latin ursus, meaning bear. -->
  <Bear.description>Ursus ist eine Gattung in der Familie der Ursidae (Bären), zu der der weit verbreitete Braunbär, der Eisbär, der amerikanische Schwarzbär und der asiatische Schwarzbär gehören. Der Name leitet sich vom lateinischen ursus ab, was Bär bedeutet.</Bear.description>
  <!-- EN: bison -->
  <Bison.label>Bison</Bison.label>
  <!-- EN: The American bison or simply bison (Bison bison), also commonly known as the American buffalo or simply buffalo, is an American species of bison that once roamed North America in vast herds. Its historical range, by 9000 BCE, is described as the great bison belt, a tract of rich grassland that ran from Alaska to the Gulf of Mexico, east to the Atlantic Seaboard (nearly to the Atlantic tidewater in some areas) as far north as New York and south to Georgia and, according to some sources, down to Florida, with sightings in North Carolina near Buffalo Ford on the Catawba River as late as 1750. It nearly became extinct by a combination of commercial hunting and slaughter in the 19th century and introduction of bovine diseases from domestic cattle. With a population in excess of 60 million in the late 18th century, the species was down to 541 animals by 1889. Recovery efforts expanded in the mid-20th century, with a resurgence to roughly 31,000 animals today, largely restricted to a few national parks and reserves. Through multiple reintroductions, the species is now also freely roaming wild in some regions in Yakutia as well as Mexico. -->
  <Bison.description>Der Amerikanische Bison oder einfach Bison (Bison bison), auch allgemein bekannt als Amerikanischer Büffel oder einfach Büffel, ist eine amerikanische Bisonart, die einst in riesigen Herden durch Nordamerika zog. Sein historisches Verbreitungsgebiet um 9000 v. Chr. wird als der große Bisongürtel beschrieben, ein Gebiet mit fruchtbarem Grasland, das sich von Alaska bis zum Golf von Mexiko, östlich bis zur Atlantikküste (in einigen Gebieten fast bis zum Atlantik), nördlich bis nach New York und südlich bis nach Georgia und einigen Quellen zufolge bis nach Florida erstreckte, wobei er noch um 1750 in North Carolina in der Nähe von Buffalo Ford am Catawba River gesichtet wurde. Durch eine Kombination aus kommerzieller Jagd und Schlachtung im 19. Jahrhundert und der Einschleppung von Rinderkrankheiten durch Hausrinder wurde er fast ausgerottet. Während die Population im späten 18. Jahrhundert mehr als 60 Millionen Tiere umfasste, war sie 1889 auf 541 Tiere geschrumpft. Mitte des 20. Jahrhunderts wurden die Bemühungen um eine Wiederansiedlung ausgeweitet, so dass es heute wieder etwa 31 000 Tiere gibt, die weitgehend auf einige Nationalparks und Reservate beschränkt sind. Durch mehrere Wiederansiedlungen lebt die Art heute auch in einigen Regionen Jakutiens und Mexikos in freier Wildbahn.</Bison.description>
  <!-- EN: boomalopes -->
  <Boomalope.label>Boomalopes</Boomalope.label>
  <!-- EN: Engineered for chemicals production, the boomalope grows a large sac of volatile chemicals on its back. Though it is weak and fragile for its size, other animals have learned to avoid it because of the huge explosion it produces when it dies. It can be milked to produce chemfuel - very carefully. -->
  <Boomalope.description>Die Boomalope wurde für die Produktion von Chemikalien entwickelt und trägt einen großen Beutel mit flüchtigen Chemikalien auf ihrem Rücken. Obwohl sie für ihre Größe schwach und zerbrechlich ist, haben andere Tiere gelernt, sie zu meiden, weil sie eine riesige Explosion erzeugt, wenn sie stirbt. Sie kann gemolken werden, um Chemikalientreibstoff zu produzieren - mit großer Vorsicht.</Boomalope.description>
  <!-- EN: camels -->
  <Camel.label>Kamele</Camel.label>
  <!-- EN: A camel is an even-toed ungulate in the genus Camelus that bears distinctive fatty deposits known as "humps" on its back. Camels have long been domesticated and, as livestock, they provide food (milk and meat) and textiles (fiber and felt from hair). Camels are working animals especially suited to their desert habitat and are a vital means of transport for passengers and cargo. There are three surviving species of camel. The one-humped dromedary makes up 94% of the world's camel population, and the two-humped Bactrian camel makes up 6%. The Wild Bactrian camel is a separate species and is now critically endangered. -->
  <Camel.description>Ein Kamel ist ein Paarhufer der Gattung Camelus, das charakteristische Fettpolster auf dem Rücken trägt, die als "Höcker" bekannt sind. Kamele werden seit langem domestiziert und liefern als Nutztiere Nahrung (Milch und Fleisch) und Textilien (Fasern und Filz aus Haaren). Kamele sind Arbeitstiere, die besonders gut an ihren Lebensraum in der Wüste angepasst sind und ein wichtiges Transportmittel für Passagiere und Fracht darstellen. Es gibt drei überlebende Arten von Kamelen. Das einhöckrige Dromedar macht 94 % der weltweiten Kamelpopulation aus, und das zweihöckrige Trampeltier macht 6 % aus. Das wilde Trampeltier ist eine eigenständige Art, die inzwischen vom Aussterben bedroht ist.</Camel.description>
  <!-- EN: cattle -->
  <Cow.label>Vieh</Cow.label>
  <!-- EN: Cattle, or cows (female) and bulls (male), are the most common type of large domesticated ungulates. They are a prominent modern member of the subfamily Bovinae, are the most widespread species of the genus Bos, and are most commonly classified collectively as Bos taurus. -->
  <Cow.description>Rinder, oder Kühe (weiblich) und Bullen (männlich), sind die häufigste Art der großen domestizierten Huftiere. Sie gehören zur Unterfamilie der Rinder (Bovinae), sind die am weitesten verbreitete Art der Gattung Bos und werden meist unter dem Namen Bos taurus zusammengefasst.</Cow.description>
  <!-- EN: deers -->
  <Deer.label>Hirsche</Deer.label>
  <!-- EN: Deer or true deer are hoofed ruminant mammals forming the family Cervidae. The two main groups of deer are the Cervinae, including the muntjac, the elk (wapiti), the red deer, the fallow deer, and the chital; and the Capreolinae, including the reindeer (caribou), the roe deer, the mule deer, and the moose. Female reindeer, and male deer of all species except the Chinese water deer, grow and shed new antlers each year. In this they differ from permanently horned antelope, which are part of a different family (Bovidae) within the same order of even-toed ungulates (Artiodactyla). -->
  <Deer.description>Hirsche oder echte Hirsche sind wiederkäuende Säugetiere mit Hufen, die zur Familie der Cervidae gehören. Die beiden Hauptgruppen der Hirsche sind die Cervinae, zu denen der Muntjac, der Elch (Wapiti), der Rothirsch, der Damhirsch und der Chital</Deer.description>
  <!-- EN: donkeys -->
  <Donkey.label>Esel</Donkey.label>
  <!-- EN: The donkey or ass (Equus africanus asinus) is a domesticated member of the horse family, Equidae. The wild ancestor of the donkey is the African wild ass, E. africanus. The donkey has been used as a working animal for at least 5000 years. There are more than 40 million donkeys in the world, mostly in underdeveloped countries, where they are used principally as draught or pack animals. Working donkeys are often associated with those living at or below subsistence levels. Small numbers of donkeys are kept for breeding or as pets in developed countries. -->
  <Donkey.description>Der Esel (Equus africanus asinus) ist ein domestiziertes Mitglied der Pferdefamilie, Equidae. Der wilde Vorfahre des Esels ist der afrikanische Wildesel, E. africanus. Der Esel wird seit mindestens 5000 Jahren als Arbeitstier genutzt. Weltweit gibt es mehr als 40 Millionen Esel, meist in unterentwickelten Ländern, wo sie hauptsächlich als Zug- oder Lasttiere eingesetzt werden. Arbeitsesel werden oft mit Menschen in Verbindung gebracht, die am oder unter dem Existenzminimum leben. In den Industrieländern werden Esel in geringer Zahl zu Zuchtzwecken oder als Haustiere gehalten.</Donkey.description>
  <!-- EN: elephants -->
  <Elephant.label>Elefanten</Elephant.label>
  <!-- EN: Elephants are the largest existing land animals. Three species are currently recognised: the African bush elephant, the African forest elephant, and the Asian elephant. Elephantidae is the only surviving family of the order Proboscidea; extinct members include the mastodons. The family Elephantidae also contains several now-extinct groups, including the mammoths and straight-tusked elephants. African elephants have larger ears and concave backs, whereas Asian elephants have smaller ears, and convex or level backs. Distinctive features of all elephants include a long proboscis called a trunk, tusks, large ear flaps, massive legs, and tough but sensitive skin. The trunk is used for breathing, bringing food and water to the mouth, and grasping objects. Tusks, which are derived from the incisor teeth, serve both as weapons and as tools for moving objects and digging. The large ear flaps assist in maintaining a constant body temperature as well as in communication. The pillar-like legs carry their great weight. -->
  <Elephant.description>Elefanten sind die größten existierenden Landtiere. Derzeit sind drei Arten bekannt: der afrikanische Buschelefant, der afrikanische Waldelefant und der asiatische Elefant. Elephantidae ist die einzige überlebende Familie der Ordnung Proboscidea</Elephant.description>
  <!-- EN: fishers -->
  <Fisher.label>fischer</Fisher.label>
  <!-- EN: The fisher (Pekania pennanti) is a small, carnivorous mammal native to North America. It is a member of the mustelid family (commonly referred to as the weasel family), and is in the monospecific genus Pekania. The fisher is closely related to, but larger than, the American marten (Martes americana). The fisher is a forest-dwelling creature whose range covers much of the boreal forest in Canada to the northern United States. Names derived from aboriginal languages include pekan, pequam, wejack, and woolang. It is sometimes misleadingly referred to as a fisher cat, although it is not a cat. -->
  <Fisher.description>Der Fischer (Pekania pennanti) ist ein kleines, fleischfressendes Säugetier, das in Nordamerika heimisch ist. Er gehört zur Familie der Schnurrbarttiere (gemeinhin als Wiesel bezeichnet) und ist Teil der monospezifischen Gattung Pekania. Der Fischer ist eng mit dem amerikanischen Marder (Martes americana) verwandt, aber größer als dieser. Der Fischer ist ein Waldbewohner, dessen Verbreitungsgebiet einen Großteil der borealen Wälder Kanadas bis in den Norden der Vereinigten Staaten umfasst. Zu den Namen, die aus den Sprachen der Ureinwohner stammen, gehören pekan, pequam, wejack und woolang. Sie wird manchmal irreführend als Fischerkatze bezeichnet, obwohl sie keine Katze ist.</Fisher.description>
  <!-- EN: giraffes -->
  <Giraffe.label>Giraffen</Giraffe.label>
  <!-- EN: The giraffe (Giraffa) is an African artiodactyl mammal, the tallest living terrestrial animal and the largest ruminant. It is traditionally considered to be one species, Giraffa camelopardalis, with nine subspecies. However, the existence of up to eight extant giraffe species has been described, based upon research into the mitochondrial and nuclear DNA, as well as morphological measurements of Giraffa. Seven other species are extinct, prehistoric species known from fossils. -->
  <Giraffe.description>Die Giraffe (Giraffa) ist ein afrikanisches Säugetier, das größte lebende Landtier und der größte Wiederkäuer. Sie wird traditionell als eine Art, Giraffa camelopardalis, mit neun Unterarten betrachtet. Auf der Grundlage von Untersuchungen der mitochondrialen und nuklearen DNA sowie von morphologischen Messungen der Giraffa wurde jedoch die Existenz von bis zu acht weiteren Giraffenarten beschrieben. Sieben weitere Arten sind ausgestorbene, prähistorische Arten, die aus Fossilien bekannt sind.</Giraffe.description>
  <!-- EN: goats -->
  <Goat.label>Ziegen</Goat.label>
  <!-- EN: The domestic goat or simply goat (Capra aegagrus hircus) is a subspecies of C. aegagrus domesticated from the wild goat of Southwest Asia and Eastern Europe. The goat is a member of the animal family Bovidae and the subfamily Caprinae, meaning it is closely related to the sheep. There are over 300 distinct breeds of goat. It is one of the oldest domesticated species of animal, according to archaeological evidence that its earliest domestication occurred in Iran at 10,000 calibrated calendar years ago. -->
  <Goat.description>Die Hausziege oder einfach Ziege (Capra aegagrus hircus) ist eine Unterart der C. aegagrus, die aus der Wildziege Südwestasiens und Osteuropas domestiziert wurde. Die Ziege gehört zur Tierfamilie der Bovidae und zur Unterfamilie der Caprinae, d. h. sie ist eng mit dem Schaf verwandt. Es gibt über 300 verschiedene Rassen von Ziegen. Sie ist eine der ältesten domestizierten Tierarten. Archäologische Beweise belegen, dass die früheste Domestizierung im Iran vor 10.000 kalibrierten Kalenderjahren stattfand.</Goat.description>
  <!-- EN: gorillas -->
  <Gorilla.label>Gorillas</Gorilla.label>
  <!-- EN: Gorillas are ground-dwelling, predominantly herbivorous great apes that inhabit the tropical forests of central Sub-Saharan Africa. The genus Gorilla is divided into two species: the eastern gorillas and the western gorillas, and either four or five subspecies. They are the largest living primates. The DNA of gorillas is highly similar to that of humans, from 95 to 99% depending on what is included, and they are the next closest living relatives to humans after chimpanzees and bonobos. -->
  <Gorilla.description>Gorillas sind bodenbewohnende, vorwiegend pflanzenfressende Menschenaffen, die in den tropischen Wäldern des zentralen Afrikas südlich der Sahara leben. Die Gattung Gorilla wird in zwei Arten unterteilt: die Östlichen Gorillas und die Westlichen Gorillas sowie vier oder fünf Unterarten. Sie sind die größten lebenden Primaten. Die DNA der Gorillas ist der des Menschen sehr ähnlich, je nach Art zwischen 95 und 99 %, und sie sind nach Schimpansen und Bonobos die nächsten lebenden Verwandten des Menschen.</Gorilla.description>
  <!-- EN: hedgehogs -->
  <Hedgehog.label>Igel</Hedgehog.label>
  <!-- EN: A hedgehog is any of the spiny mammals of the subfamily Erinaceinae, in the eulipotyphlan family Erinaceidae. There are seventeen species of hedgehog in five genera found through parts of Europe, Asia, and Africa, and in New Zealand by introduction. There are no hedgehogs native to Australia and no living species native to the Americas (the extinct genus Amphechinus was once present in North America). -->
  <Hedgehog.description>Ein Igel ist eines der stacheligen Säugetiere der Unterfamilie Erinaceinae in der Familie der Eulipotyphlane Erinaceidae. Es gibt siebzehn Igelarten in fünf Gattungen, die in Teilen Europas, Asiens und Afrikas sowie in Neuseeland heimisch sind. In Australien sind keine Igel heimisch und in Amerika gibt es keine lebenden Arten (die ausgestorbene Gattung Amphechinus war einst in Nordamerika heimisch).</Hedgehog.description>
  <!-- EN: hippopotamus -->
  <Hippopotamus.label>Nilpferd</Hippopotamus.label>
  <!-- EN: The hippopotamus (Hippopotamus amphibius), also called the hippo, common hippopotamus or river hippopotamus, is a large, mostly herbivorous, semiaquatic mammal and ungulate native to sub-Saharan Africa. It is one of only two extant species in the family Hippopotamidae, the other being the pygmy hippopotamus (Choeropsis liberiensis or Hexaprotodon liberiensis). The name comes from the ancient Greek for "river horse" (ἱπποπόταμος). -->
  <Hippopotamus.description>Das Flusspferd (Hippopotamus amphibius), auch Nilpferd, Flusspferd oder Flusspferd genannt, ist ein großes, meist pflanzenfressendes, halbwässriges Säugetier und Huftier, das in Afrika südlich der Sahara heimisch ist. Es ist eine von nur zwei lebenden Arten der Familie Hippopotamidae, die andere ist das Zwergflusspferd (Choeropsis liberiensis oder Hexaprotodon liberiensis). Der Name stammt aus dem Altgriechischen und bedeutet "Flusspferd" (ἱπποπόταμος).</Hippopotamus.description>
  <!-- EN: horses -->
  <Horse.label>Pferde</Horse.label>
  <!-- EN: The wild horse (Equus ferus) is a species of the genus Equus, which includes as subspecies the modern domesticated horse (Equus ferus caballus) as well as the undomesticated tarpan (Equus ferus ferus, now extinct), and the endangered Przewalski's horse (Equus ferus przewalskii). -->
  <Horse.description>Das Wildpferd (Equus ferus) ist eine Art der Gattung Equus, die als Unterarten das moderne Hauspferd (Equus ferus caballus) sowie den undomestizierten Tarpan (Equus ferus ferus, heute ausgestorben) und das gefährdete Przewalski-Pferd (Equus ferus przewalskii) umfasst.</Horse.description>
  <!-- EN: kangaroos -->
  <Kangaroo.label>Kängurus</Kangaroo.label>
  <!-- EN: The kangaroo is a marsupial from the family Macropodidae (macropods, meaning "large foot"). In common use the term is used to describe the largest species from this family, the red kangaroo, as well as the antilopine kangaroo, eastern grey kangaroo, and western grey kangaroo. Kangaroos are indigenous to Australia and New Guinea. The Australian government estimates that 34.3 million kangaroos lived within the commercial harvest areas of Australia in 2011, up from 25.1 million one year earlier. -->
  <Kangaroo.description>Das Känguru ist ein Beuteltier aus der Familie der Makropodidae (Makropoden, was "großer Fuß" bedeutet). Im allgemeinen Sprachgebrauch wird der Begriff verwendet, um die größte Art dieser Familie, das Rote Känguru, sowie das Antilopin-Känguru, das Östliche Graue Känguru und das Westliche Graue Känguru zu beschreiben. Kängurus sind in Australien und Neuguinea beheimatet. Die australische Regierung schätzt, dass im Jahr 2011 34,3 Millionen Kängurus in den kommerziellen Erntegebieten Australiens lebten, gegenüber 25,1 Millionen im Jahr zuvor.</Kangaroo.description>
  <!-- EN: leviathans -->
  <Leviathan.label>Leviathane</Leviathan.label>
  <!-- EN: Leviathans are giant predatores found in the coldest biomes of the planets.Leviathans are extremely strong and good wool producers but not easy to tame. Different leviathan subspecies live in the jungle and the arid biomes. -->
  <Leviathan.description>Leviathane sind riesige Raubtiere, die in den kältesten Biomen der Planeten leben. Leviathane sind extrem stark und gute Wollproduzenten, aber nicht leicht zu zähmen. Verschiedene Unterarten von Leviathanen leben im Dschungel und in den Trockenbiomen.</Leviathan.description>
  <!-- EN: martens -->
  <Marten.label>Marder</Marten.label>
  <!-- EN: The martens constitute the genus Martes within the subfamily Guloninae, in the family Mustelidae. They have bushy tails and large paws with partially retractile claws. The fur varies from yellowish to dark brown, depending on the species, and is valued by trappers for the fur trade. Martens are slender, agile animals, adapted to living in the taiga, and inhabit coniferous and northern deciduous forests across the Northern Hemisphere. -->
  <Marten.description>Die Marder bilden die Gattung Martes innerhalb der Unterfamilie Guloninae, in der Familie Mustelidae. Sie haben buschige Schwänze und große Pfoten mit teilweise einziehbaren Krallen. Das Fell variiert je nach Art von gelblich bis dunkelbraun und wird von Fallenstellern für den Pelzhandel geschätzt. Marder sind schlanke, wendige Tiere, die an das Leben in der Taiga angepasst sind und Nadel- und nördliche Laubwälder auf der gesamten Nordhalbkugel bewohnen.</Marten.description>
  <!-- EN: monkeys -->
  <Monkey.label>Affen</Monkey.label>
  <!-- EN: Monkey is a common name that may refer to certain groups or species of simian mammals of infraorder Simiiformes. The term is applied descriptively to groups of primates, such as families of New World monkeys and Old World monkeys. Many monkey species are tree-dwelling (arboreal), although there are species that live primarily on the ground, such as baboons. Most species are mainly active during the day (diurnal). Monkeys are generally considered to be intelligent, especially the Old World monkeys of Catarrhini. -->
  <Monkey.description>Affe ist ein gebräuchlicher Name, der sich auf bestimmte Gruppen oder Arten von Affensäugetieren der Unterordnung Simiiformes beziehen kann. Der Begriff wird beschreibend auf Gruppen von Primaten angewandt, wie z. B. die Familien der Neuweltaffen und der Altweltäffchen. Viele Affenarten leben in Bäumen (arboreal), es gibt jedoch auch Arten, die sich hauptsächlich auf dem Boden aufhalten, wie z. B. Paviane. Die meisten Arten sind hauptsächlich tagsüber aktiv (tagaktiv). Affen gelten im Allgemeinen als intelligent, insbesondere die Altweltaffen der Catarrhini.</Monkey.description>
  <!-- EN: opossums -->
  <Opossum.label>Opossums</Opossum.label>
  <!-- EN: Opossums are members of the marsupial order Didelphimorphia endemic to the Americas. The largest order of marsupials in the Western Hemisphere, it comprises 120+ species in 19 genera. Opossums originated in South America and entered North America in the Great American Interchange following the connection of North and South America. -->
  <Opossum.description>Opossums sind Mitglieder der Beuteltierordnung Didelphimorphia, die auf dem amerikanischen Kontinent endemisch ist. Sie ist die größte Ordnung der Beuteltiere in der westlichen Hemisphäre und umfasst 120 Arten in 19 Gattungen. Opossums stammen ursprünglich aus Südamerika und gelangten im Zuge des Großen Amerikanischen Austauschs, der auf die Verbindung von Nord- und Südamerika folgte, nach Nordamerika.</Opossum.description>
  <!-- EN: otters -->
  <Otter.label>Otter</Otter.label>
  <!-- EN: Otters are carnivorous mammals in the subfamily Lutrinae. The 13 extant otter species are all semiaquatic, aquatic or marine, with diets based on fish and invertebrates. Lutrinae is a branch of the Mustelidae family, which also includes weasels, badgers, mink, and wolverines, among other animals. -->
  <Otter.description>Otter sind fleischfressende Säugetiere aus der Unterfamilie der Lutrinae. Die 13 existierenden Otterarten sind alle semiaquatisch, aquatisch oder marin und ernähren sich von Fischen und wirbellosen Tieren. Die Lutrinae sind ein Zweig der Familie der Mustelidae, zu der unter anderem auch Wiesel, Dachse, Nerze und Vielfraße gehören.</Otter.description>
  <!-- EN: pandas -->
  <Panda.label>Pandas</Panda.label>
  <!-- EN: The giant panda (Ailuropoda melanoleuca), also known as the panda bear or simply the panda, is a bear native to South Central China. It is characterised by its bold black-and-white coat and rotund body. The name "giant panda" is sometimes used to distinguish it from the red panda, a neighboring musteloid. Though it belongs to the order Carnivora, the giant panda is a folivore, with bamboo shoots and leaves making up more than 99% of its diet. Giant pandas in the wild will occasionally eat other grasses, wild tubers, or even meat in the form of birds, rodents, or carrion. In captivity, they may receive honey, eggs, fish, yams, shrub leaves, oranges, or bananas along with specially prepared food. -->
  <Panda.description>Der Große Panda (Ailuropoda melanoleuca), auch bekannt als Pandabär oder einfach Panda, ist ein Bär, der im südlichen Zentralchina heimisch ist. Er zeichnet sich durch sein auffälliges schwarz-weißes Fell und seinen rundlichen Körper aus. Der Name "Riesenpanda" wird manchmal verwendet, um ihn vom Roten Panda, einem benachbarten Musteloiden, zu unterscheiden. Obwohl er zur Ordnung der Fleischfresser (Carnivora) gehört, ist der Große Panda ein Blattfresser, wobei Bambussprossen und Blätter mehr als 99 % seiner Nahrung ausmachen. In freier Wildbahn fressen Große Pandas gelegentlich auch andere Gräser, wilde Knollen oder sogar Fleisch in Form von Vögeln, Nagetieren oder Aas. In Gefangenschaft können sie Honig, Eier, Fisch, Süßkartoffeln, Blätter von Sträuchern, Orangen oder Bananen zusammen mit speziell zubereitetem Futter erhalten.</Panda.description>
  <!-- EN: pangolins -->
  <Pangolin.label>Schuppentiere</Pangolin.label>
  <!-- EN: Pangolins, sometimes known as scaly anteaters, are mammals of the order Pholidota (/fɒlɪˈdoʊtə/, from Ancient Greek ϕολιδωτός 'clad in scales'). The one extant family, Manidae, has three genera: Manis, Phataginus and Smutsia. Manis comprises the four species found in Asia, while Phataginus and Smutsia include two species each, all found in sub-Saharan Africa. These species range in size from 30 to 100 cm (12 to 39 in). A number of extinct pangolin species are also known. -->
  <Pangolin.description>Schuppentiere, manchmal auch als Ameisenbären bekannt, sind Säugetiere der Ordnung Pholidota (/fɒlɪˈdoʊtə/, von altgriechisch ϕολιδωτός 'mit Schuppen bedeckt'). Die einzige noch existierende Familie, Manidae, hat drei Gattungen: Manis, Phataginus und Smutsia. Manis umfasst die vier in Asien vorkommenden Arten, während Phataginus und Smutsia jeweils zwei Arten umfassen, die alle in Afrika südlich der Sahara vorkommen. Die Größe dieser Arten reicht von 30 bis 100 cm (12 bis 39 Zoll). Es sind auch einige ausgestorbene Schuppentierarten bekannt.</Pangolin.description>
  <!-- EN: pigs -->
  <Pig.label>schweine</Pig.label>
  <!-- EN: A pig is any of the animals in the genus Sus, within the even-toed ungulate family Suidae. Pigs include domestic pigs and their ancestor, the common Eurasian wild boar (Sus scrofa), along with other species. Pigs, like all suids, are native to the Eurasian and African continents, ranging from Europe to the Pacific islands. Suids other than the pig are the babirusa of Indonesia, the pygmy hog of South Asia, the warthog of Africa, and another genus of pigs from Africa. The suids are a sister clade to peccaries. -->
  <Pig.description>Ein Schwein ist ein Tier der Gattung Sus aus der Familie der Paarhufer (Suidae). Zu den Schweinen gehören Hausschweine und ihr Vorfahre, das gewöhnliche eurasische Wildschwein (Sus scrofa), sowie andere Arten. Wie alle Suidae sind Schweine auf dem eurasischen und afrikanischen Kontinent beheimatet und reichen von Europa bis zu den pazifischen Inseln. Andere Suiden als das Schwein sind das Babirusa aus Indonesien, das Zwergschwein aus Südasien, das Warzenschwein aus Afrika und eine weitere Schweinegattung aus Afrika. Die Suiden sind eine Schwestergattung der Pekaris.</Pig.description>
  <!-- EN: red pandas -->
  <RedPanda.label>Rote Pandas</RedPanda.label>
  <!-- EN: The red panda (Ailurus fulgens) is a carnivoran native to the eastern Himalayas and southwestern China. It is listed as Endangered on the IUCN Red List because the wild population is estimated at fewer than 10,000 mature individuals and continues to decline due to habitat loss and fragmentation, poaching, and inbreeding depression. Despite its name, it is not closely related to the giant panda. -->
  <RedPanda.description>Der Rote Panda (Ailurus fulgens) ist ein Fleischfresser, der im östlichen Himalaya und im südwestlichen China beheimatet ist. Er wird auf der Roten Liste der IUCN als gefährdet geführt, da die Wildpopulation auf weniger als 10.000 geschlechtsreife Exemplare geschätzt wird und aufgrund von Lebensraumverlust und -zerschneidung, Wilderei und Inzuchtdepression weiter abnimmt. Trotz seines Namens ist er nicht eng mit dem Großen Panda verwandt.</RedPanda.description>
  <!-- EN: rhinoceros -->
  <Rhinoceros.label>rhinoceros</Rhinoceros.label>
  <!-- EN: A rhinoceros (Greek rhinokerōs 'nose-horned', from rhis 'nose', and keras 'horn'), commonly abbreviated to rhino, is a member of any of the five extant species of odd-toed ungulates in the family Rhinocerotidae, as well as any of the numerous extinct species therein. Two of the extant species are native to Africa, and three to Southern Asia. The term "rhinoceros" is often more broadly applied to now extinct species of the superfamily Rhinocerotoidea. -->
  <Rhinoceros.description>Ein Nashorn (griechisch rhinokerōs 'Nase', von rhis 'Nase' und keras 'Horn'), allgemein abgekürzt als Rhinozeros, ist ein Mitglied einer der fünf existierenden Arten von Unpaarhufern in der Familie Rhinocerotidae, sowie einer der zahlreichen ausgestorbenen Arten darin. Zwei der existierenden Arten sind in Afrika beheimatet, drei in Südasien. Der Begriff "Nashorn" wird häufig im weiteren Sinne auf heute ausgestorbene Arten der Überfamilie Rhinocerotoidea angewandt.</Rhinoceros.description>
  <!-- EN: seals -->
  <Seal.label>Siegel</Seal.label>
  <!-- EN: The earless seals, phocids or true seals are one of the three main groups of mammals within the seal lineage, Pinnipedia. All true seals are members of the family Phocidae. They are sometimes called crawling seals to distinguish them from the fur seals and sea lions of the family Otariidae. Seals live in the oceans of both hemispheres and, with the exception of the more tropical monk seals, are mostly confined to polar, subpolar, and temperate climates. The Baikal seal is the only species of exclusively freshwater seal. -->
  <Seal.description>Die ohrlosen Robben, Phociden oder echten Robben sind eine der drei Hauptgruppen von Säugetieren innerhalb der Robbenlinie, Pinnipedia. Alle echten Robben sind Mitglieder der Familie Phocidae. Sie werden manchmal auch Krabbelrobben genannt, um sie von den Pelzrobben und Seelöwen der Familie Otariidae zu unterscheiden. Robben leben in den Ozeanen beider Hemisphären und sind, mit Ausnahme der tropischen Mönchsrobben, meist auf die polaren, subpolaren und gemäßigten Klimazonen beschränkt. Die Baikalrobbe ist die einzige Robbenart, die ausschließlich im Süßwasser lebt.</Seal.description>
  <!-- EN: sheeps -->
  <Sheep.label>Schafe</Sheep.label>
  <!-- EN: Sheep (Ovis aries) are quadrupedal, ruminant mammals typically kept as livestock. Like most ruminants, sheep are members of the order Artiodactyla, the even-toed ungulates. Although the name sheep applies to many species in the genus Ovis, in everyday usage it almost always refers to Ovis aries. Numbering a little over one billion, domestic sheep are also the most numerous species of sheep. An adult female is referred to as a ewe, an intact male as a ram, occasionally a tup, a castrated male as a wether, and a young sheep as a lamb. -->
  <Sheep.description>Schafe (Ovis aries) sind vierfüßige, wiederkäuende Säugetiere, die typischerweise als Nutztiere gehalten werden. Wie die meisten Wiederkäuer gehören Schafe zur Ordnung der Paarhufer, den Artiodactyla. Obwohl der Name Schaf auf viele Arten der Gattung Ovis zutrifft, bezieht er sich im Alltagsgebrauch fast immer auf Ovis aries. Mit etwas mehr als einer Milliarde Exemplare sind Hausschafe auch die zahlreichste Schafsart. Ein erwachsenes weibliches Schaf wird als Mutterschaf bezeichnet, ein intaktes männliches Schaf als Widder, gelegentlich auch als Jungschaf, ein kastriertes männliches Schaf als Mutterschaf und ein junges Schaf als Lamm.</Sheep.description>
  <!-- EN: tanays -->
  <Tanay.label>tanays</Tanay.label>
  <!-- EN: Tanay are large herbivores engineered to produce large anmounts of neutroamine. -->
  <Tanay.description>Tanay sind große Pflanzenfresser, die so konstruiert sind, dass sie große Mengen an Neutroamin produzieren.</Tanay.description>
  <!-- EN: tapirs -->
  <Tapir.label>Tapire</Tapir.label>
  <!-- EN: A tapir is a large, herbivorous mammal, similar in shape to a pig, with a short, prehensile nose trunk. Tapirs inhabit jungle and forest regions of South America, Central America, and Southeast Asia. There are four widely recognized extant species of tapirs, all of the family Tapiridae and the genus Tapirus. They are the Brazilian tapir, the Malayan tapir, the Baird's tapir, and the mountain tapir. The four species that have been evaluated are all classified on the IUCN Red List as Endangered or Vulnerable. The tapirs have a number of extinct relatives in the superfamily Tapiroidea. The closest extant relatives of the tapirs are the other odd-toed ungulates, which include horses, donkeys, zebras and rhinoceroses. -->
  <Tapir.description>Ein Tapir ist ein großes, pflanzenfressendes Säugetier, das in seiner Form einem Schwein ähnelt und einen kurzen, mit Greifzähnen versehenen Rüssel hat. Tapire bewohnen Dschungel- und Waldregionen in Südamerika, Mittelamerika und Südostasien. Es gibt vier weithin anerkannte Arten von Tapiren, die alle zur Familie der Tapiridae und zur Gattung Tapirus gehören. Es handelt sich um den Brasilianischen Tapir, den Malaiischen Tapir, den Baird-Tapir und den Bergtapir. Die vier untersuchten Arten sind in der Roten Liste der IUCN als gefährdet oder anfällig eingestuft. Die Tapire haben eine Reihe von ausgestorbenen Verwandten in der Überfamilie der Tapiroidea. Die nächsten lebenden Verwandten der Tapire sind die anderen Unpaarhufer, zu denen Pferde, Esel, Zebras und Nashörner gehören.</Tapir.description>
  <!-- EN: tasmanian devils -->
  <TasmanianDevil.label>Tasmanische Teufel</TasmanianDevil.label>
  <!-- EN: The Tasmanian devil (Sarcophilus harrisii) is a carnivorous marsupial of the family Dasyuridae. Until recently, it was only found on the island state of Tasmania, but it has now been reintroduced to New South Wales, with a small breeding population. The size of a small dog, the Tasmanian devil became the largest carnivorous marsupial in the world, following the extinction of the thylacine in 1936. It is related to quolls, and distantly related to the thylacine. It is characterised by its stocky and muscular build, black fur, pungent odour, extremely loud and disturbing screech, keen sense of smell, and ferocity when feeding. The Tasmanian devil's large head and neck allow it to generate among the strongest bites per unit body mass of any extant predatory land mammal. It hunts prey and scavenges on carrion. -->
  <TasmanianDevil.description>Der Tasmanische Teufel (Sarcophilus harrisii) ist ein fleischfressendes Beuteltier aus der Familie der Dasyuridae. Bis vor kurzem kam er nur auf dem Inselstaat Tasmanien vor, doch inzwischen wurde er in New South Wales wieder angesiedelt, wo er eine kleine Zuchtpopulation bildet. Der Tasmanische Teufel, der die Größe eines kleinen Hundes hat, war nach dem Aussterben des Thylacine im Jahr 1936 das größte fleischfressende Beuteltier der Welt. Er ist mit den Quolls und entfernt mit dem Thylacine verwandt. Er zeichnet sich durch seinen stämmigen und muskulösen Körperbau, sein schwarzes Fell, seinen stechenden Geruch, sein extrem lautes und beunruhigendes Kreischen, seinen scharfen Geruchssinn und seine Wildheit beim Fressen aus. Dank seines großen Kopfes und Halses ist der Tasmanische Teufel in der Lage, im Verhältnis zur Körpermasse mit die stärksten Bisse aller existierenden räuberischen Landsäugetiere zu erzeugen. Er jagt Beutetiere und ernährt sich von Aas.</TasmanianDevil.description>
  <!-- EN: thrumbos -->
  <Thrumbo.label>thrumbos</Thrumbo.label>
  <!-- EN: A gigantic, graceful creature of unknown origin. The thrumbo is gentle by nature, but extremely dangerous when enraged. While its long fur is exceptionally beautiful, its hide is also incredibly resistant to damage. Its razor-sharp horn fetches a huge price.\n\nLegends say that an old thrumbo is the wisest creature in the universe - it simply chooses not to speak. -->
  <Thrumbo.description>Eine gigantische, anmutige Kreatur unbekannter Herkunft. Der Thrumbo ist von Natur aus sanftmütig, aber extrem gefährlich, wenn er wütend ist. Sein langes Fell ist außergewöhnlich schön, aber sein Fell ist auch unglaublich widerstandsfähig. Sein rasiermesserscharfes Horn bringt einen hohen Preis ein.

Die Legende besagt, dass ein alter Thrumbo das weiseste Wesen im Universum ist - er entscheidet sich einfach dafür, nicht zu sprechen.</Thrumbo.description>
  <!-- EN: walruses -->
  <Walrus.label>Walrösser</Walrus.label>
  <!-- EN: The walrus (Odobenus rosmarus) is a large flippered marine mammal with a discontinuous distribution about the North Pole in the Arctic Ocean and subarctic seas of the Northern Hemisphere. The walrus is the only living species in the family Odobenidae and genus Odobenus. This species is subdivided into two subspecies: the Atlantic walrus (O. r. rosmarus), which lives in the Atlantic Ocean, and the Pacific walrus (O. r. divergens), which lives in the Pacific Ocean. -->
  <Walrus.description>Das Walross (Odobenus rosmarus) ist ein großer, flossenbewehrter Meeressäuger mit einer diskontinuierlichen Verbreitung um den Nordpol im Arktischen Ozean und den subarktischen Meeren der nördlichen Hemisphäre. Das Walross ist die einzige lebende Art aus der Familie der Odobenidae und der Gattung Odobenus. Diese Art wird in zwei Unterarten unterteilt: das Atlantische Walross (O. r. rosmarus), das im Atlantischen Ozean lebt, und das Pazifische Walross (O. r. divergens), das im Pazifischen Ozean lebt.</Walrus.description>
  <!-- EN: whales -->
  <Whale.label>Wale</Whale.label>
  <!-- EN: Whales are a widely distributed and diverse group of fully aquatic placental marine mammals. They are an informal grouping within the infraorder Cetacea, usually excluding dolphins and porpoises. Whales, dolphins and porpoises belong to the order Cetartiodactyla, which consists of even-toed ungulates. Their closest living relatives are the hippopotamuses, having diverged about 40 million years ago. The two parvorders of whales, baleen whales (Mysticeti) and toothed whales (Odontoceti), are thought to have split apart around 34 million years ago. Whales consist of eight extant families: Balaenopteridae (the rorquals), Balaenidae (right whales), Cetotheriidae (the pygmy right whale), Eschrichtiidae (the grey whale), Monodontidae (belugas and narwhals), Physeteridae (the sperm whale), Kogiidae (the dwarf and pygmy sperm whale), and Ziphiidae (the beaked whales). -->
  <Whale.description>Wale sind eine weit verbreitete und vielfältige Gruppe von voll aquatischen, plazentaren Meeressäugern. Sie sind eine informelle Gruppierung innerhalb der Unterordnung Cetacea, die normalerweise Delfine und Schweinswale ausschließt. Wale, Delfine und Schweinswale gehören zur Ordnung der Paarhufer (Cetartiodactyla), die aus Paarhufern besteht. Ihre engsten lebenden Verwandten sind die Flusspferde, die sich vor etwa 40 Millionen Jahren getrennt haben. Es wird angenommen, dass sich die beiden Unterordnungen der Wale, die Bartenwale (Mysticeti) und die Zahnwale (Odontoceti), vor etwa 34 Millionen Jahren getrennt haben. Die Wale bestehen aus acht Familien, die noch existieren: Balaenopteridae (Schwertwale), Balaenidae (Glattwale), Cetotheriidae (Zwergglattwale), Eschrichtiidae (Grauwale), Monodontidae (Belugas und Narwale), Physeteridae (Pottwale), Kogiidae (Zwerg- und Pygmäen-Pottwale) und Ziphiidae (Schnabelwale).</Whale.description>
  <!-- EN: wombats -->
  <Wombat.label>Wombats</Wombat.label>
  <!-- EN: Wombats are short-legged, muscular quadrupedal marsupials that are native to Australia. They are about 1 m (40 in) in length with small, stubby tails and weigh between 20 and 35 kg (44 and 77 lb). There are three extant species and they are all members of the family Vombatidae. They are adaptable and habitat tolerant, and are found in forested, mountainous, and heathland areas of southern and eastern Australia, including Tasmania, as well as an isolated patch of about 300 ha (740 acres) in Epping Forest National Park in central Queensland. -->
  <Wombat.description>Wombats sind kurzbeinige, muskulöse vierfüßige Beuteltiere, die in Australien heimisch sind. Sie sind etwa 1 m lang, haben kleine, stumpfe Schwänze und wiegen zwischen 20 und 35 kg. Es gibt drei existierende Arten, die alle zur Familie der Vombatidae gehören. Sie sind anpassungsfähig und lebensraumtolerant und kommen in bewaldeten, bergigen und heidnischen Gebieten im südlichen und östlichen Australien, einschließlich Tasmanien, sowie in einem isolierten Gebiet von etwa 300 ha im Epping Forest National Park in Zentral-Queensland vor.</Wombat.description>
  <!-- EN: zebras -->
  <Zebra.label>Zebras</Zebra.label>
  <!-- EN: Zebras (subgenus Hippotigris) are African equines with distinctive black-and-white striped coats. There are three extant species: the Grévy's zebra (Equus grevyi), plains zebra (E. quagga), and the mountain zebra (E. zebra). Zebras share the genus Equus with horses and asses, the three groups being the only living members of the family Equidae. Zebra stripes come in different patterns, unique to each individual. Several theories have been proposed for the function of these stripes, with most evidence supporting them as a form of protection from biting flies. Zebras inhabit eastern and southern Africa and can be found in a variety of habitats such as savannahs, grasslands, woodlands, shrublands, and mountainous areas. -->
  <Zebra.description>Zebras (Untergattung Hippotigris) sind afrikanische Equiden mit einem charakteristischen schwarz-weiß gestreiften Fell. Es gibt drei Arten: das Grévy-Zebra (Equus grevyi), das Steppenzebra (E. quagga) und das Bergzebra (E. zebra). Zebras teilen sich die Gattung Equus mit Pferden und Eseln; die drei Gruppen sind die einzigen lebenden Mitglieder der Familie Equidae. Zebrastreifen gibt es in verschiedenen Mustern, die für jedes Individuum einzigartig sind. Es gibt mehrere Theorien über die Funktion dieser Streifen, wobei die meisten Beweise dafür sprechen, dass sie eine Art Schutz vor Stechfliegen darstellen. Zebras sind im östlichen und südlichen Afrika beheimatet und kommen in einer Vielzahl von Lebensräumen wie Savannen, Grasland, Wäldern, Buschland und Bergregionen vor.</Zebra.description>
</LanguageData>
