<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <!--The following translations were generated by https://www.deepl.com/-->
  <!-- EN: dogs -->
  <Dog.label>chiens</Dog.label>
  <!-- EN: The dog (Canis familiaris when considered a distinct species or Canis lupus familiaris when considered a subspecies of the wolf) is a member of the genus Canis (canines), which forms part of the wolf-like canids, and is the most widely abundant terrestrial carnivore. The dog and the extant gray wolf are sister taxa as modern wolves are not closely related to the wolves that were first domesticated, which implies that the direct ancestor of the dog is extinct. The dog was the first species to be domesticated, and has been selectively bred over millennia for various behaviors, sensory capabilities, and physical attributes. -->
  <Dog.description>Le chien (Canis familiaris lorsqu'il est considéré comme une espèce distincte ou Canis lupus familiaris lorsqu'il est considéré comme une sous-espèce de loup) est un membre du genre Canis (canines), qui fait partie des canidés de type loup, et est le carnivore terrestre le plus répandu. Le chien et le loup gris actuel sont des taxons frères, car les loups modernes ne sont pas étroitement liés aux loups qui ont été domestiqués pour la première fois, ce qui implique que l'ancêtre direct du chien est éteint. Le chien a été la première espèce à être domestiquée et a fait l'objet d'un élevage sélectif au cours des millénaires pour divers comportements, capacités sensorielles et attributs physiques.</Dog.description>
  <!-- EN: foxes -->
  <Fox.label>renards</Fox.label>
  <!-- EN: Vulpes is a genus of the Caninae. The members of this genus are colloquially referred to as true foxes, meaning they form a proper clade. The word "fox" occurs on the common names of species. True foxes are distinguished from members of the genus Canis, such as domesticated dogs, wolves, jackals and coyotes, by their smaller size (5–11 kg) and flatter skull. They have black, triangular markings between their eyes and nose, and the tip of their tail is often a different color from the rest of their pelt. The typical lifespan for this genus is between two and four years, but can reach up to a decade. -->
  <Fox.description>Vulpes est un genre de la famille des Caninae. Les membres de ce genre sont familièrement appelés "vrais renards", ce qui signifie qu'ils forment un clade à part entière. Le mot "renard" figure dans le nom commun des espèces. Les vrais renards se distinguent des membres du genre Canis, tels que les chiens domestiques, les loups, les chacals et les coyotes, par leur taille plus petite (5-11 kg) et leur crâne plus plat. Ils ont des marques noires triangulaires entre les yeux et le nez, et le bout de leur queue est souvent d'une couleur différente du reste de leur pelage. L'espérance de vie typique de ce genre se situe entre deux et quatre ans, mais peut atteindre une dizaine d'années.</Fox.description>
  <!-- EN: hyenas -->
  <Hyena.label>hyènes</Hyena.label>
  <!-- EN: Hyenas, or hyaenas (from Ancient Greek ὕαινα, hýaina), are feliform carnivoran mammals of the family Hyaenidae. With only four extant species (in three genera), it is the fifth-smallest biological family in the Carnivora and one of the smallest in the class Mammalia. Despite their low diversity, hyenas are unique and vital components of most African ecosystems. -->
  <Hyena.description>Les hyènes, ou hyaenas (du grec ancien ὕαινα, hýaina), sont des mammifères carnivores féliformes de la famille des Hyaenidae. Avec seulement quatre espèces existantes (réparties en trois genres), il s'agit de la cinquième plus petite famille biologique des Carnivora et de l'une des plus petites de la classe des Mammalia. Malgré leur faible diversité, les hyènes sont des éléments uniques et vitaux de la plupart des écosystèmes africains.</Hyena.description>
  <!-- EN: tanukis -->
  <Tanuki.label>tanukis</Tanuki.label>
  <!-- EN: The Japanese raccoon dog (Nyctereutes procyonoides viverrinus), also known as the tanuki (Japanese: タヌキ or 狸; pronounced [taꜜnɯki]), is a subspecies of the Asian raccoon dog. Researchers have suggested that they be considered a separate species, N. viverrinus, or that raccoon dogs of Japan could be further divisible into separate subspecies as N. p. procyonoides (hondo-tanuki, ホンドタヌキ, 本土狸) and N. p. albus (ezo-tanuki, エゾタヌキ, 蝦夷狸), but both views are controversial. -->
  <Tanuki.description>Le chien viverrin japonais (Nyctereutes procyonoides viverrinus), également connu sous le nom de tanuki (japonais : タヌキ ou 狸</Tanuki.description>
  <!-- EN: wargs -->
  <Warg.label>wargs</Warg.label>
  <!-- EN: The dire wolf (Canis dirus, "fearsome dog") is an extinct species of the genus Canis. It is one of the most famous prehistoric carnivores in North America, along with its extinct competitor, the sabre-toothed cat Smilodon fatalis. The dire wolf lived in the Americas during the Late Pleistocene and Early Holocene epochs (125,000–9,500 years ago). The species was named in 1858, four years after the first specimen had been found. Two subspecies are recognized: Canis dirus guildayi and Canis dirus dirus. The dire wolf probably evolved from Armbruster's wolf (Canis armbrusteri) in North America. The largest collection of its fossils has been obtained from the Rancho La Brea Tar Pits in Los Angeles. -->
  <Warg.description>Le loup sinistre (Canis dirus, "chien redoutable") est une espèce éteinte du genre Canis. C'est l'un des carnivores préhistoriques les plus célèbres d'Amérique du Nord, avec son concurrent disparu, le chat à dents de sabre Smilodon fatalis. Le grand loup vivait en Amérique à l'époque du Pléistocène tardif et de l'Holocène précoce (il y a 125 000 à 9 500 ans). L'espèce a été nommée en 1858, quatre ans après la découverte du premier spécimen. Deux sous-espèces sont reconnues : Canis dirus guildayi et Canis dirus dirus. Le loup sauvage a probablement évolué à partir du loup d'Armbruster (Canis armbrusteri) en Amérique du Nord. La plus grande collection de ses fossiles provient des fosses de goudron de Rancho La Brea à Los Angeles.</Warg.description>
  <!-- EN: wolves -->
  <Wolf.label>loups</Wolf.label>
  <!-- EN: The wolf (Canis lupus), also known as the "gray wolf" or "grey wolf", is a large canine native to Eurasia and North America. It is the largest extant member of Canidae, males averaging 40 kg (88 lb) and females 37 kg (82 lb). On average, wolves measure 105–160 cm (41–63 in) in length and 80–85 cm (31–33 in) at shoulder height. The wolf is also distinguished from other Canis species by its less pointed ears and muzzle, as well as a shorter torso and a longer tail. The wolf is nonetheless related closely enough to smaller Canis species, such as the coyote and the golden jackal, to produce fertile hybrids with them. The banded fur of a wolf is usually mottled white, brown, gray, and black. Up to 38 subspecies of wolf have been recognized including the domestic dog. -->
  <Wolf.description>Le loup (Canis lupus), également connu sous le nom de "loup gris", est un grand canidé originaire d'Eurasie et d'Amérique du Nord. C'est le plus grand membre existant des Canidés, les mâles pesant en moyenne 40 kg et les femelles 37 kg. En moyenne, les loups mesurent 105 à 160 cm de long et 80 à 85 cm à hauteur des épaules. Le loup se distingue également des autres espèces de Canis par des oreilles et un museau moins pointus, ainsi que par un torse plus court et une queue plus longue. Le loup est néanmoins suffisamment proche des espèces Canis plus petites, comme le coyote et le chacal doré, pour produire des hybrides fertiles avec eux. Le pelage rayé du loup est généralement tacheté de blanc, de brun, de gris et de noir. Jusqu'à 38 sous-espèces de loups ont été reconnues, y compris le chien domestique.</Wolf.description>
</LanguageData>
