<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <!--The following translations were generated by https://www.deepl.com/-->
  <!-- EN: cats -->
  <Cat.label>chats</Cat.label>
  <!-- EN: Felis is a genus of small and medium-sized cat species native to most of Africa and south of 60° latitude in Europe and Asia to Indochina. The genus includes the domestic cat. The smallest Felis species is the black-footed cat with a head and body length from 38 to 42 cm (15 to 17 in). The largest is the jungle cat with a head and body length from 62 to 76 cm (24 to 30 in). -->
  <Cat.description>Felis est un genre d'espèces de chats de petite et moyenne taille originaires de la majeure partie de l'Afrique et au sud du 60e parallèle en Europe et en Asie jusqu'à l'Indochine. Le genre comprend le chat domestique. La plus petite espèce de Felis est le chat à pattes noires, dont la tête et le corps mesurent de 38 à 42 cm (15 à 17 pouces). Le plus grand est le chat de la jungle, dont la tête et le corps mesurent de 62 à 76 cm (24 à 30 pouces).</Cat.description>
  <!-- EN: cheetahs -->
  <Cheetah.label>guépards</Cheetah.label>
  <!-- EN: The cheetah (Acinonyx jubatus) is a large cat native to Africa and central Iran. It is the fastest land animal, capable of running at 80 to 128 km/h (50 to 80 mph), and as such has several adaptations for speed, including a light build, long thin legs and a long tail. Cheetahs typically reach 67–94 cm (26–37 in) at the shoulder, and the head-and-body length is between 1.1 and 1.5 m (3.6 and 4.9 ft). Adults typically weigh between 20 and 65 kg (44 and 143 lb). Its head is small, rounded, and has a short snout and black tear-like facial streaks. The coat is typically tawny to creamy white or pale buff and is mostly covered with evenly spaced, solid black spots. Four subspecies are recognised. -->
  <Cheetah.description>Le guépard (Acinonyx jubatus) est un grand félin originaire d'Afrique et d'Iran central. C'est l'animal terrestre le plus rapide, capable de courir à une vitesse comprise entre 80 et 128 km/h. Il possède donc plusieurs adaptations à la vitesse, notamment une corpulence légère, de longues pattes fines et une longue queue. Les guépards atteignent généralement 67 à 94 cm au niveau de l'épaule, et la longueur de la tête et du corps se situe entre 1,1 et 1,5 m (3,6 et 4,9 pieds). Les adultes pèsent généralement entre 20 et 65 kg. Sa tête est petite, arrondie, avec un museau court et des stries faciales noires en forme de larmes. Son pelage est généralement de couleur fauve à blanc crème ou chamois pâle et est principalement recouvert de taches noires unies régulièrement espacées. Quatre sous-espèces sont reconnues.</Cheetah.description>
  <!-- EN: jaguars -->
  <Jaguar.label>jaguars</Jaguar.label>
  <!-- EN: The jaguar (Panthera onca) is a large felid species and the only extant member of the genus Panthera native to the Americas. The jaguar's present range extends from Southwestern United States and Mexico in North America, across much of Central America, and south to Paraguay and northern Argentina in South America. Though there are single cats now living within the Western United States, the species has largely been extirpated from the United States since the early 20th century. It is listed as Near Threatened on the IUCN Red List; and its numbers are declining. Threats include loss and fragmentation of habitat. -->
  <Jaguar.description>Le jaguar (Panthera onca) est un grand félin et le seul membre du genre Panthera originaire des Amériques. L'aire de répartition actuelle du jaguar s'étend du sud-ouest des États-Unis et du Mexique en Amérique du Nord, à travers une grande partie de l'Amérique centrale, et au sud jusqu'au Paraguay et au nord de l'Argentine en Amérique du Sud. Bien qu'il existe aujourd'hui des chats isolés dans l'ouest des États-Unis, l'espèce a largement disparu de ce pays depuis le début du XXe siècle. Elle figure sur la liste rouge de l'UICN en tant qu'espèce quasi-menacée</Jaguar.description>
  <!-- EN: leopards -->
  <Leopard.label>léopards</Leopard.label>
  <!-- EN: The leopard (Panthera pardus) is one of the five extant species in the genus Panthera, a member of the Felidae. It occurs in a wide range in sub-Saharan Africa, in small parts of Western and Central Asia, on the Indian subcontinent to Southeast and East Asia. It is listed as Vulnerable on the IUCN Red List because leopard populations are threatened by habitat loss and fragmentation, and are declining in large parts of the global range. In Hong Kong, Singapore, Kuwait, Syria, Libya, Tunisia and most likely in Morocco, leopard populations have already been extirpated. Contemporary records suggest that the leopard occurs in only 25% of its historical global range. -->
  <Leopard.description>Le léopard (Panthera pardus) est l'une des cinq espèces existantes du genre Panthera, membre de la famille des Felidae. Il est présent dans une large aire de répartition en Afrique subsaharienne, dans de petites parties de l'Asie occidentale et centrale, sur le sous-continent indien jusqu'en Asie du Sud-Est et de l'Est. Il est classé comme vulnérable sur la liste rouge de l'UICN car les populations de léopards sont menacées par la perte et la fragmentation de l'habitat et sont en déclin dans de grandes parties de l'aire de répartition mondiale. À Hong Kong, à Singapour, au Koweït, en Syrie, en Libye, en Tunisie et très probablement au Maroc, les populations de léopards ont déjà disparu. Les données contemporaines suggèrent que le léopard n'est présent que dans 25 % de son aire de répartition historique mondiale.</Leopard.description>
  <!-- EN: lions -->
  <Lion.label>lions</Lion.label>
  <!-- EN: The lion (Panthera leo) is a species in the family Felidae; it is a muscular, deep-chested cat with a short, rounded head, a reduced neck and round ears, and a hairy tuft at the end of its tail. It is sexually dimorphic; adult male lions have a prominent mane, which is the most recognisable feature of the species. With a typical head-to-body length of 184–208 cm (72–82 in) they are larger than females at 160–184 cm (63–72 in). It is a social species, forming groups called prides. A lion pride consists of a few adult males, related females and cubs. Groups of female lions usually hunt together, preying mostly on large ungulates. The lion is an apex and keystone predator, although some lions scavenge when opportunities occur, and have been known to hunt humans, although the species typically does not. -->
  <Lion.description>Le lion (Panthera leo) est une espèce de la famille des Felidae.</Lion.description>
  <!-- EN: snow leopards -->
  <SnowLeopard.label>léopards des neiges</SnowLeopard.label>
  <!-- EN: The snow leopard (Panthera uncia), also known as the ounce, is a large cat native to the mountain ranges of Central and South Asia. It is listed as Vulnerable on the IUCN Red List because the global population is estimated to number less than 10,000 mature individuals and is expected to decline about 10% by 2040. It is threatened by poaching and habitat destruction following infrastructural developments. It inhabits alpine and subalpine zones at elevations from 3,000 to 4,500 m (9,800 to 14,800 ft), ranging from eastern Afghanistan, the Himalayas and the Tibetan Plateau, to southern Siberia, Mongolia, and western China. In the countries in the northern part of its range, it also lives at lower elevations. -->
  <SnowLeopard.description>Le léopard des neiges (Panthera uncia), également connu sous le nom d'once, est un grand félin originaire des chaînes montagneuses d'Asie centrale et du Sud. Il figure sur la liste rouge de l'UICN dans la catégorie "vulnérable", car la population mondiale est estimée à moins de 10 000 individus matures et devrait diminuer d'environ 10 % d'ici à 2040. Il est menacé par le braconnage et la destruction de son habitat suite au développement d'infrastructures. Il habite les zones alpines et subalpines à des altitudes de 3 000 à 4 500 m, depuis l'est de l'Afghanistan, l'Himalaya et le plateau tibétain, jusqu'au sud de la Sibérie, la Mongolie et l'ouest de la Chine. Dans les pays situés dans la partie septentrionale de son aire de répartition, il vit également à des altitudes plus basses.</SnowLeopard.description>
  <!-- EN: tigers -->
  <Tiger.label>tigres</Tiger.label>
  <!-- EN: The tiger (Panthera tigris) is the largest extant cat species and a member of the genus Panthera. It is most recognisable for its dark vertical stripes on orange-brown fur with a lighter underside. It is an apex predator, primarily preying on ungulates such as deer and wild boar. It is territorial and generally a solitary but social predator, requiring large contiguous areas of habitat, which support its requirements for prey and rearing of its offspring. Tiger cubs stay with their mother for about two years, before they become independent and leave their mother's home range to establish their own. -->
  <Tiger.description>Le tigre (Panthera tigris) est la plus grande espèce de félin existante et un membre du genre Panthera. Il est reconnaissable à ses rayures verticales foncées sur une fourrure brun-orange dont le dessous est plus clair. C'est un prédateur du sommet de la chaîne, qui s'attaque principalement aux ongulés tels que les cerfs et les sangliers. C'est un prédateur territorial, généralement solitaire mais social, qui a besoin de vastes zones d'habitat contiguës pour satisfaire ses besoins en proies et élever sa progéniture. Les petits tigres restent avec leur mère pendant environ deux ans, avant de devenir indépendants et de quitter le domaine vital de leur mère pour établir le leur.</Tiger.description>
</LanguageData>
