<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <!--The following translations were generated by https://www.deepl.com/-->
  <!-- EN: antelopes -->
  <Antelope.label>antilopes</Antelope.label>
  <!-- EN: The term antelope is used to refer to many species of even-toed ruminant indigenous to various regions in Africa and Eurasia. Antelope comprise a wastebasket taxon (miscellaneous group) within the family Bovidae, encompassing all Old World ruminants that are not bovines, sheep, or goats. A group of antelope is called a herd. Unlike deer antlers, which are shed and grown annually, antelope horns grow continuously. -->
  <Antelope.description>Le terme antilope est utilisé pour désigner de nombreuses espèces de ruminants à doigts pairs originaires de diverses régions d'Afrique et d'Eurasie. Les antilopes constituent un taxon poubelle (groupe divers) au sein de la famille des Bovidae, englobant tous les ruminants de l'Ancien Monde qui ne sont pas des bovins, des moutons ou des chèvres. Un groupe d'antilopes s'appelle un troupeau. Contrairement aux bois des cervidés, qui tombent et poussent chaque année, les cornes des antilopes poussent continuellement.</Antelope.description>
  <!-- EN: armadillos -->
  <Armadillo.label>tatous</Armadillo.label>
  <!-- EN: Armadillos (meaning "little armored ones" in Spanish) are New World placental mammals in the order Cingulata. The Chlamyphoridae and Dasypodidae are the only surviving families in the order, which is part of the superorder Xenarthra, along with the anteaters and sloths. Nine extinct genera and 21 extant species of armadillo have been described, some of which are distinguished by the number of bands on their armor. All species are native to the Americas, where they inhabit a variety of different environments. -->
  <Armadillo.description>Les tatous (qui signifient "petites armures" en espagnol) sont des mammifères placentaires du Nouveau Monde appartenant à l'ordre des Cingulata. Les Chlamyphoridae et les Dasypodidae sont les seules familles survivantes de cet ordre, qui fait partie du superordre des Xenarthra, avec les fourmiliers et les paresseux. Neuf genres éteints et 21 espèces de tatou ont été décrits, dont certains se distinguent par le nombre de bandes sur leur armure. Toutes les espèces sont originaires des Amériques, où elles vivent dans des environnements variés.</Armadillo.description>
  <!-- EN: badgers -->
  <Badger.label>blaireaux</Badger.label>
  <!-- EN: Badgers are short-legged omnivores mostly in the family Mustelidae (which also includes the otters, polecats, weasels, and ferrets), but also with two species called "badgers" in the related family Mephitidae (which also includes the skunks). Badgers are a polyphyletic grouping, and are not a natural taxonomic grouping: badgers are united by their squat bodies, adapted for fossorial activity. All belong to the caniform suborder of carnivoran mammals. -->
  <Badger.description>Les blaireaux sont des omnivores à pattes courtes appartenant principalement à la famille des Mustélidés (qui comprend également les loutres, les putois, les belettes et les furets), mais aussi à deux espèces appelées "blaireaux" dans la famille apparentée des Méphitidés (qui comprend également les moufettes). Le blaireau est un groupe polyphylétique, qui n'est pas un groupe taxonomique naturel : les blaireaux sont unis par leur corps trapu, adapté à l'activité fossile. Tous appartiennent au sous-ordre caniforme des mammifères carnivores.</Badger.description>
  <!-- EN: bears -->
  <Bear.label>ours</Bear.label>
  <!-- EN: Ursus is a genus in the family Ursidae (bears) that includes the widely distributed brown bear, the polar bear, the American black bear, and the Asian black bear. The name is derived from the Latin ursus, meaning bear. -->
  <Bear.description>Ursus est un genre de la famille des Ursidae (ours) qui comprend l'ours brun, largement répandu, l'ours polaire, l'ours noir américain et l'ours noir asiatique. Le nom est dérivé du latin ursus, qui signifie ours.</Bear.description>
  <!-- EN: bison -->
  <Bison.label>bison</Bison.label>
  <!-- EN: The American bison or simply bison (Bison bison), also commonly known as the American buffalo or simply buffalo, is an American species of bison that once roamed North America in vast herds. Its historical range, by 9000 BCE, is described as the great bison belt, a tract of rich grassland that ran from Alaska to the Gulf of Mexico, east to the Atlantic Seaboard (nearly to the Atlantic tidewater in some areas) as far north as New York and south to Georgia and, according to some sources, down to Florida, with sightings in North Carolina near Buffalo Ford on the Catawba River as late as 1750. It nearly became extinct by a combination of commercial hunting and slaughter in the 19th century and introduction of bovine diseases from domestic cattle. With a population in excess of 60 million in the late 18th century, the species was down to 541 animals by 1889. Recovery efforts expanded in the mid-20th century, with a resurgence to roughly 31,000 animals today, largely restricted to a few national parks and reserves. Through multiple reintroductions, the species is now also freely roaming wild in some regions in Yakutia as well as Mexico. -->
  <Bison.description>Le bison d'Amérique ou simplement bison (Bison bison), également connu sous le nom de buffle d'Amérique ou simplement buffle, est une espèce américaine de bison qui parcourait autrefois l'Amérique du Nord en vastes troupeaux. Son aire de répartition historique, qui remonte à 9000 ans avant notre ère, est décrite comme la grande ceinture du bison, une zone de riches prairies qui s'étendait de l'Alaska au golfe du Mexique, à l'est de la côte atlantique (presque jusqu'à la marée de l'Atlantique dans certaines régions) jusqu'à New York au nord et jusqu'à la Géorgie au sud et, selon certaines sources, jusqu'à la Floride, avec des observations en Caroline du Nord près de Buffalo Ford sur la rivière Catawba jusqu'en 1750. Il a failli disparaître en raison de la chasse commerciale et de l'abattage au XIXe siècle, ainsi que de l'introduction de maladies bovines provenant du bétail domestique. Avec une population de plus de 60 millions d'individus à la fin du XVIIIe siècle, l'espèce ne comptait plus que 541 animaux en 1889. Les efforts de rétablissement se sont intensifiés au milieu du 20e siècle, avec une résurgence d'environ 31 000 animaux aujourd'hui, en grande partie limités à quelques parcs nationaux et réserves. Grâce à de multiples réintroductions, l'espèce se trouve aujourd'hui en liberté dans certaines régions de Yakoutie ainsi qu'au Mexique.</Bison.description>
  <!-- EN: boomalopes -->
  <Boomalope.label>boomalopes</Boomalope.label>
  <!-- EN: Engineered for chemicals production, the boomalope grows a large sac of volatile chemicals on its back. Though it is weak and fragile for its size, other animals have learned to avoid it because of the huge explosion it produces when it dies. It can be milked to produce chemfuel - very carefully. -->
  <Boomalope.description>Conçu pour la production de produits chimiques, le boomalope porte sur son dos une grande poche de produits chimiques volatils. Bien qu'il soit faible et fragile pour sa taille, les autres animaux ont appris à l'éviter à cause de l'énorme explosion qu'il produit lorsqu'il meurt. Il est possible de le traire pour produire du carburant chimique - avec beaucoup de précautions.</Boomalope.description>
  <!-- EN: camels -->
  <Camel.label>chameaux</Camel.label>
  <!-- EN: A camel is an even-toed ungulate in the genus Camelus that bears distinctive fatty deposits known as "humps" on its back. Camels have long been domesticated and, as livestock, they provide food (milk and meat) and textiles (fiber and felt from hair). Camels are working animals especially suited to their desert habitat and are a vital means of transport for passengers and cargo. There are three surviving species of camel. The one-humped dromedary makes up 94% of the world's camel population, and the two-humped Bactrian camel makes up 6%. The Wild Bactrian camel is a separate species and is now critically endangered. -->
  <Camel.description>Un chameau est un ongulé à doigts pairs du genre Camelus qui porte sur le dos des dépôts graisseux distinctifs appelés "bosses". Les chameaux sont domestiqués depuis longtemps et, en tant que bétail, ils fournissent de la nourriture (lait et viande) et des textiles (fibre et feutre à partir des poils). Les chameaux sont des animaux de travail particulièrement adaptés à leur habitat désertique et constituent un moyen de transport essentiel pour les passagers et les marchandises. Trois espèces de chameaux ont survécu. Le dromadaire à une bosse représente 94 % de la population mondiale de chameaux, et le chameau de Bactriane à deux bosses en représente 6 %. Le chameau sauvage de Bactriane est une espèce distincte, aujourd'hui en danger critique d'extinction.</Camel.description>
  <!-- EN: cattle -->
  <Cow.label>bétail</Cow.label>
  <!-- EN: Cattle, or cows (female) and bulls (male), are the most common type of large domesticated ungulates. They are a prominent modern member of the subfamily Bovinae, are the most widespread species of the genus Bos, and are most commonly classified collectively as Bos taurus. -->
  <Cow.description>Les bovins, ou vaches (femelles) et taureaux (mâles), sont le type le plus commun de grands ongulés domestiqués. Ils constituent un membre moderne important de la sous-famille des Bovinae, sont l'espèce la plus répandue du genre Bos et sont le plus souvent classés collectivement sous le nom de Bos taurus.</Cow.description>
  <!-- EN: deers -->
  <Deer.label>deers</Deer.label>
  <!-- EN: Deer or true deer are hoofed ruminant mammals forming the family Cervidae. The two main groups of deer are the Cervinae, including the muntjac, the elk (wapiti), the red deer, the fallow deer, and the chital; and the Capreolinae, including the reindeer (caribou), the roe deer, the mule deer, and the moose. Female reindeer, and male deer of all species except the Chinese water deer, grow and shed new antlers each year. In this they differ from permanently horned antelope, which are part of a different family (Bovidae) within the same order of even-toed ungulates (Artiodactyla). -->
  <Deer.description>Les cerfs ou vrais cervidés sont des mammifères ruminants à sabots appartenant à la famille des Cervidés. Les deux principaux groupes de cerfs sont les Cervinae, qui comprennent le muntjac, l'élan (wapiti), le cerf rouge, le daim et le chital.</Deer.description>
  <!-- EN: donkeys -->
  <Donkey.label>ânes</Donkey.label>
  <!-- EN: The donkey or ass (Equus africanus asinus) is a domesticated member of the horse family, Equidae. The wild ancestor of the donkey is the African wild ass, E. africanus. The donkey has been used as a working animal for at least 5000 years. There are more than 40 million donkeys in the world, mostly in underdeveloped countries, where they are used principally as draught or pack animals. Working donkeys are often associated with those living at or below subsistence levels. Small numbers of donkeys are kept for breeding or as pets in developed countries. -->
  <Donkey.description>L'âne (Equus africanus asinus) est un membre domestique de la famille des chevaux, les Equidae. L'ancêtre sauvage de l'âne est l'âne sauvage africain, E. africanus. L'âne est utilisé comme animal de trait depuis au moins 5 000 ans. Il y a plus de 40 millions d'ânes dans le monde, principalement dans les pays sous-développés, où ils sont utilisés comme animaux de trait ou de bât. Les ânes de travail sont souvent associés à ceux qui vivent au niveau de subsistance ou en dessous. Dans les pays développés, un petit nombre d'ânes sont élevés pour la reproduction ou comme animaux de compagnie.</Donkey.description>
  <!-- EN: elephants -->
  <Elephant.label>éléphants</Elephant.label>
  <!-- EN: Elephants are the largest existing land animals. Three species are currently recognised: the African bush elephant, the African forest elephant, and the Asian elephant. Elephantidae is the only surviving family of the order Proboscidea; extinct members include the mastodons. The family Elephantidae also contains several now-extinct groups, including the mammoths and straight-tusked elephants. African elephants have larger ears and concave backs, whereas Asian elephants have smaller ears, and convex or level backs. Distinctive features of all elephants include a long proboscis called a trunk, tusks, large ear flaps, massive legs, and tough but sensitive skin. The trunk is used for breathing, bringing food and water to the mouth, and grasping objects. Tusks, which are derived from the incisor teeth, serve both as weapons and as tools for moving objects and digging. The large ear flaps assist in maintaining a constant body temperature as well as in communication. The pillar-like legs carry their great weight. -->
  <Elephant.description>Les éléphants sont les plus grands animaux terrestres existants. Trois espèces sont actuellement reconnues : l'éléphant de brousse africain, l'éléphant de forêt africain et l'éléphant d'Asie. Les éléphantidés sont la seule famille survivante de l'ordre des proboscidés.</Elephant.description>
  <!-- EN: fishers -->
  <Fisher.label>pêcheurs</Fisher.label>
  <!-- EN: The fisher (Pekania pennanti) is a small, carnivorous mammal native to North America. It is a member of the mustelid family (commonly referred to as the weasel family), and is in the monospecific genus Pekania. The fisher is closely related to, but larger than, the American marten (Martes americana). The fisher is a forest-dwelling creature whose range covers much of the boreal forest in Canada to the northern United States. Names derived from aboriginal languages include pekan, pequam, wejack, and woolang. It is sometimes misleadingly referred to as a fisher cat, although it is not a cat. -->
  <Fisher.description>Le pékan (Pekania pennanti) est un petit mammifère carnivore originaire d'Amérique du Nord. Il fait partie de la famille des mustélidés (communément appelée famille des belettes), et appartient au genre monospécifique Pekania. Le pékan est étroitement lié à la martre d'Amérique (Martes americana), mais il est plus grand qu'elle. Le pékan est un animal forestier dont l'aire de répartition s'étend de la forêt boréale du Canada au nord des États-Unis. Les noms dérivés des langues autochtones comprennent pekan, pequam, wejack et woolang. Il est parfois appelé à tort chat pêcheur, bien qu'il ne s'agisse pas d'un chat.</Fisher.description>
  <!-- EN: giraffes -->
  <Giraffe.label>girafes</Giraffe.label>
  <!-- EN: The giraffe (Giraffa) is an African artiodactyl mammal, the tallest living terrestrial animal and the largest ruminant. It is traditionally considered to be one species, Giraffa camelopardalis, with nine subspecies. However, the existence of up to eight extant giraffe species has been described, based upon research into the mitochondrial and nuclear DNA, as well as morphological measurements of Giraffa. Seven other species are extinct, prehistoric species known from fossils. -->
  <Giraffe.description>La girafe (Giraffa) est un mammifère artiodactyle africain, le plus grand animal terrestre vivant et le plus grand ruminant. Elle est traditionnellement considérée comme une seule espèce, Giraffa camelopardalis, avec neuf sous-espèces. Cependant, l'existence de huit espèces de girafes a été décrite sur la base de recherches sur l'ADN mitochondrial et nucléaire, ainsi que sur les mesures morphologiques de Giraffa. Sept autres espèces sont des espèces préhistoriques éteintes, connues grâce à des fossiles.</Giraffe.description>
  <!-- EN: goats -->
  <Goat.label>chèvres</Goat.label>
  <!-- EN: The domestic goat or simply goat (Capra aegagrus hircus) is a subspecies of C. aegagrus domesticated from the wild goat of Southwest Asia and Eastern Europe. The goat is a member of the animal family Bovidae and the subfamily Caprinae, meaning it is closely related to the sheep. There are over 300 distinct breeds of goat. It is one of the oldest domesticated species of animal, according to archaeological evidence that its earliest domestication occurred in Iran at 10,000 calibrated calendar years ago. -->
  <Goat.description>La chèvre domestique ou simplement chèvre (Capra aegagrus hircus) est une sous-espèce de C. aegagrus domestiquée à partir de la chèvre sauvage d'Asie du Sud-Ouest et d'Europe de l'Est. La chèvre fait partie de la famille des Bovidae et de la sous-famille des Caprinae, ce qui signifie qu'elle est étroitement liée au mouton. Il existe plus de 300 races distinctes de chèvres. La chèvre est l'une des plus anciennes espèces d'animaux domestiqués, selon des preuves archéologiques indiquant que sa domestication la plus ancienne a eu lieu en Iran il y a 10 000 années calendaires calibrées.</Goat.description>
  <!-- EN: gorillas -->
  <Gorilla.label>gorilles</Gorilla.label>
  <!-- EN: Gorillas are ground-dwelling, predominantly herbivorous great apes that inhabit the tropical forests of central Sub-Saharan Africa. The genus Gorilla is divided into two species: the eastern gorillas and the western gorillas, and either four or five subspecies. They are the largest living primates. The DNA of gorillas is highly similar to that of humans, from 95 to 99% depending on what is included, and they are the next closest living relatives to humans after chimpanzees and bonobos. -->
  <Gorilla.description>Les gorilles sont des grands singes terrestres, principalement herbivores, qui vivent dans les forêts tropicales du centre de l'Afrique subsaharienne. Le genre Gorilla est divisé en deux espèces : les gorilles de l'Est et les gorilles de l'Ouest, et en quatre ou cinq sous-espèces. Ce sont les plus grands primates vivants. L'ADN des gorilles est très similaire à celui des humains, de 95 à 99 % selon les éléments pris en compte, et ils sont les parents vivants les plus proches de l'homme après les chimpanzés et les bonobos.</Gorilla.description>
  <!-- EN: hedgehogs -->
  <Hedgehog.label>hérissons</Hedgehog.label>
  <!-- EN: A hedgehog is any of the spiny mammals of the subfamily Erinaceinae, in the eulipotyphlan family Erinaceidae. There are seventeen species of hedgehog in five genera found through parts of Europe, Asia, and Africa, and in New Zealand by introduction. There are no hedgehogs native to Australia and no living species native to the Americas (the extinct genus Amphechinus was once present in North America). -->
  <Hedgehog.description>Un hérisson est un mammifère épineux de la sous-famille des Erinaceinae, dans la famille eulipotyphane des Erinaceidae. Il existe dix-sept espèces de hérissons réparties en cinq genres que l'on trouve dans certaines parties de l'Europe, de l'Asie et de l'Afrique, ainsi qu'en Nouvelle-Zélande, où elles ont été introduites. Aucun hérisson n'est originaire d'Australie et aucune espèce vivante n'est originaire d'Amérique (le genre Amphechinus, aujourd'hui éteint, était autrefois présent en Amérique du Nord).</Hedgehog.description>
  <!-- EN: hippopotamus -->
  <Hippopotamus.label>hippopotame</Hippopotamus.label>
  <!-- EN: The hippopotamus (Hippopotamus amphibius), also called the hippo, common hippopotamus or river hippopotamus, is a large, mostly herbivorous, semiaquatic mammal and ungulate native to sub-Saharan Africa. It is one of only two extant species in the family Hippopotamidae, the other being the pygmy hippopotamus (Choeropsis liberiensis or Hexaprotodon liberiensis). The name comes from the ancient Greek for "river horse" (ἱπποπόταμος). -->
  <Hippopotamus.description>L'hippopotame (Hippopotamus amphibius), également appelé hippopotame, hippopotame commun ou hippopotame de rivière, est un grand mammifère semi-aquatique, principalement herbivore, et un ongulé originaire d'Afrique subsaharienne. C'est l'une des deux seules espèces existantes de la famille des Hippopotamidae, l'autre étant l'hippopotame pygmée (Choeropsis liberiensis ou Hexaprotodon liberiensis). Son nom vient du grec ancien qui signifie " cheval de rivière " (ἱπποπόταμος).</Hippopotamus.description>
  <!-- EN: horses -->
  <Horse.label>chevaux</Horse.label>
  <!-- EN: The wild horse (Equus ferus) is a species of the genus Equus, which includes as subspecies the modern domesticated horse (Equus ferus caballus) as well as the undomesticated tarpan (Equus ferus ferus, now extinct), and the endangered Przewalski's horse (Equus ferus przewalskii). -->
  <Horse.description>Le cheval sauvage (Equus ferus) est une espèce du genre Equus, qui comprend comme sous-espèces le cheval domestique moderne (Equus ferus caballus) ainsi que le tarpan non domestiqué (Equus ferus ferus, aujourd'hui éteint), et le cheval de Przewalski (Equus ferus przewalskii), une espèce en voie de disparition.</Horse.description>
  <!-- EN: kangaroos -->
  <Kangaroo.label>kangourous</Kangaroo.label>
  <!-- EN: The kangaroo is a marsupial from the family Macropodidae (macropods, meaning "large foot"). In common use the term is used to describe the largest species from this family, the red kangaroo, as well as the antilopine kangaroo, eastern grey kangaroo, and western grey kangaroo. Kangaroos are indigenous to Australia and New Guinea. The Australian government estimates that 34.3 million kangaroos lived within the commercial harvest areas of Australia in 2011, up from 25.1 million one year earlier. -->
  <Kangaroo.description>Le kangourou est un marsupial de la famille des macropodidés (macropods signifiant "grand pied"). Dans l'usage courant, le terme désigne la plus grande espèce de cette famille, le kangourou roux, ainsi que le kangourou antilopine, le kangourou gris de l'Est et le kangourou gris de l'Ouest. Les kangourous sont originaires d'Australie et de Nouvelle-Guinée. Le gouvernement australien estime que 34,3 millions de kangourous vivaient dans les zones d'exploitation commerciale de l'Australie en 2011, contre 25,1 millions un an plus tôt.</Kangaroo.description>
  <!-- EN: leviathans -->
  <Leviathan.label>léviathans</Leviathan.label>
  <!-- EN: Leviathans are giant predatores found in the coldest biomes of the planets.Leviathans are extremely strong and good wool producers but not easy to tame. Different leviathan subspecies live in the jungle and the arid biomes. -->
  <Leviathan.description>Les léviathans sont des prédateurs géants que l'on trouve dans les biomes les plus froids des planètes. Les léviathans sont extrêmement forts et de bons producteurs de laine, mais ils ne sont pas faciles à apprivoiser. Différentes sous-espèces de léviathans vivent dans la jungle et les biomes arides.</Leviathan.description>
  <!-- EN: martens -->
  <Marten.label>martres</Marten.label>
  <!-- EN: The martens constitute the genus Martes within the subfamily Guloninae, in the family Mustelidae. They have bushy tails and large paws with partially retractile claws. The fur varies from yellowish to dark brown, depending on the species, and is valued by trappers for the fur trade. Martens are slender, agile animals, adapted to living in the taiga, and inhabit coniferous and northern deciduous forests across the Northern Hemisphere. -->
  <Marten.description>Les martres constituent le genre Martes dans la sous-famille des Guloninae, dans la famille des Mustélidés. Elles ont une queue touffue et de grandes pattes aux griffes partiellement rétractables. La fourrure varie du jaunâtre au brun foncé, selon l'espèce, et est appréciée des trappeurs pour le commerce des fourrures. La martre est un animal mince et agile, adapté à la taïga, qui vit dans les forêts de conifères et de feuillus de l'hémisphère nord.</Marten.description>
  <!-- EN: monkeys -->
  <Monkey.label>singes</Monkey.label>
  <!-- EN: Monkey is a common name that may refer to certain groups or species of simian mammals of infraorder Simiiformes. The term is applied descriptively to groups of primates, such as families of New World monkeys and Old World monkeys. Many monkey species are tree-dwelling (arboreal), although there are species that live primarily on the ground, such as baboons. Most species are mainly active during the day (diurnal). Monkeys are generally considered to be intelligent, especially the Old World monkeys of Catarrhini. -->
  <Monkey.description>Singe est un nom commun qui peut désigner certains groupes ou espèces de mammifères simiens de l'infra-ordre des Simiiformes. Le terme est appliqué de manière descriptive à des groupes de primates, tels que les familles de singes du Nouveau Monde et les singes de l'Ancien Monde. De nombreuses espèces de singes vivent dans les arbres (arboricoles), bien qu'il existe des espèces qui vivent principalement au sol, comme les babouins. La plupart des espèces sont principalement actives pendant la journée (diurnes). Les singes sont généralement considérés comme intelligents, en particulier les singes de l'Ancien Monde (Catarrhini).</Monkey.description>
  <!-- EN: opossums -->
  <Opossum.label>opossums</Opossum.label>
  <!-- EN: Opossums are members of the marsupial order Didelphimorphia endemic to the Americas. The largest order of marsupials in the Western Hemisphere, it comprises 120+ species in 19 genera. Opossums originated in South America and entered North America in the Great American Interchange following the connection of North and South America. -->
  <Opossum.description>Les opossums sont des membres de l'ordre des marsupiaux Didelphimorphia endémiques des Amériques. Il s'agit du plus grand ordre de marsupiaux de l'hémisphère occidental. Il comprend 120 espèces réparties en 19 genres. Les opossums sont originaires d'Amérique du Sud et sont entrés en Amérique du Nord lors du grand échange américain qui a suivi la connexion entre l'Amérique du Nord et l'Amérique du Sud.</Opossum.description>
  <!-- EN: otters -->
  <Otter.label>loutres</Otter.label>
  <!-- EN: Otters are carnivorous mammals in the subfamily Lutrinae. The 13 extant otter species are all semiaquatic, aquatic or marine, with diets based on fish and invertebrates. Lutrinae is a branch of the Mustelidae family, which also includes weasels, badgers, mink, and wolverines, among other animals. -->
  <Otter.description>Les loutres sont des mammifères carnivores de la sous-famille des Lutrinae. Les 13 espèces de loutres existantes sont toutes semi-aquatiques, aquatiques ou marines, avec un régime alimentaire basé sur les poissons et les invertébrés. Les Lutrinae sont une branche de la famille des Mustelidae, qui comprend également les belettes, les blaireaux, les visons et les carcajous, entre autres animaux.</Otter.description>
  <!-- EN: pandas -->
  <Panda.label>pandas</Panda.label>
  <!-- EN: The giant panda (Ailuropoda melanoleuca), also known as the panda bear or simply the panda, is a bear native to South Central China. It is characterised by its bold black-and-white coat and rotund body. The name "giant panda" is sometimes used to distinguish it from the red panda, a neighboring musteloid. Though it belongs to the order Carnivora, the giant panda is a folivore, with bamboo shoots and leaves making up more than 99% of its diet. Giant pandas in the wild will occasionally eat other grasses, wild tubers, or even meat in the form of birds, rodents, or carrion. In captivity, they may receive honey, eggs, fish, yams, shrub leaves, oranges, or bananas along with specially prepared food. -->
  <Panda.description>Le panda géant (Ailuropoda melanoleuca), également connu sous le nom d'ours panda ou simplement de panda, est un ours originaire du centre-sud de la Chine. Il se caractérise par son pelage noir et blanc et sa corpulence. Le nom de "panda géant" est parfois utilisé pour le distinguer du panda roux, un mustéloïde voisin. Bien qu'il appartienne à l'ordre des carnivores, le panda géant est un folivore, les pousses et les feuilles de bambou constituant plus de 99 % de son régime alimentaire. Dans la nature, les pandas géants mangent parfois d'autres herbes, des tubercules sauvages ou même de la viande sous forme d'oiseaux, de rongeurs ou de charognes. En captivité, ils peuvent recevoir du miel, des œufs, du poisson, des ignames, des feuilles d'arbustes, des oranges ou des bananes, ainsi que des aliments spécialement préparés.</Panda.description>
  <!-- EN: pangolins -->
  <Pangolin.label>pangolins</Pangolin.label>
  <!-- EN: Pangolins, sometimes known as scaly anteaters, are mammals of the order Pholidota (/fɒlɪˈdoʊtə/, from Ancient Greek ϕολιδωτός 'clad in scales'). The one extant family, Manidae, has three genera: Manis, Phataginus and Smutsia. Manis comprises the four species found in Asia, while Phataginus and Smutsia include two species each, all found in sub-Saharan Africa. These species range in size from 30 to 100 cm (12 to 39 in). A number of extinct pangolin species are also known. -->
  <Pangolin.description>Les pangolins, parfois appelés fourmiliers écailleux, sont des mammifères de l'ordre des Pholidota (/fɒlɪˈdoʊtə/, du grec ancien ϕολιδωτός "recouvert d'écailles"). La seule famille existante, les Manidae, compte trois genres : Manis, Phataginus et Smutsia. Manis comprend les quatre espèces présentes en Asie, tandis que Phataginus et Smutsia comprennent deux espèces chacun, toutes présentes en Afrique subsaharienne. La taille de ces espèces varie de 30 à 100 cm. Un certain nombre d'espèces de pangolins éteintes sont également connues.</Pangolin.description>
  <!-- EN: pigs -->
  <Pig.label>cochons</Pig.label>
  <!-- EN: A pig is any of the animals in the genus Sus, within the even-toed ungulate family Suidae. Pigs include domestic pigs and their ancestor, the common Eurasian wild boar (Sus scrofa), along with other species. Pigs, like all suids, are native to the Eurasian and African continents, ranging from Europe to the Pacific islands. Suids other than the pig are the babirusa of Indonesia, the pygmy hog of South Asia, the warthog of Africa, and another genus of pigs from Africa. The suids are a sister clade to peccaries. -->
  <Pig.description>Un porc est un animal du genre Sus, appartenant à la famille des ongulés à doigts pairs Suidae. Les cochons comprennent les cochons domestiques et leur ancêtre, le sanglier commun d'Eurasie (Sus scrofa), ainsi que d'autres espèces. Les porcs, comme tous les suidés, sont originaires des continents eurasien et africain, de l'Europe aux îles du Pacifique. Les suidés autres que le porc sont le babirusa d'Indonésie, le porc pygmée d'Asie du Sud, le phacochère d'Afrique et un autre genre de porc d'Afrique. Les suidés sont un clade frère des pécaris.</Pig.description>
  <!-- EN: red pandas -->
  <RedPanda.label>pandas rouges</RedPanda.label>
  <!-- EN: The red panda (Ailurus fulgens) is a carnivoran native to the eastern Himalayas and southwestern China. It is listed as Endangered on the IUCN Red List because the wild population is estimated at fewer than 10,000 mature individuals and continues to decline due to habitat loss and fragmentation, poaching, and inbreeding depression. Despite its name, it is not closely related to the giant panda. -->
  <RedPanda.description>Le panda roux (Ailurus fulgens) est un carnivore originaire de l'est de l'Himalaya et du sud-ouest de la Chine. Il est inscrit sur la liste rouge de l'UICN dans la catégorie "en danger" car la population sauvage est estimée à moins de 10 000 individus matures et continue de décliner en raison de la perte et de la fragmentation de l'habitat, du braconnage et de la dépression due à la consanguinité. Malgré son nom, il n'est pas étroitement lié au panda géant.</RedPanda.description>
  <!-- EN: rhinoceros -->
  <Rhinoceros.label>rhinocéros</Rhinoceros.label>
  <!-- EN: A rhinoceros (Greek rhinokerōs 'nose-horned', from rhis 'nose', and keras 'horn'), commonly abbreviated to rhino, is a member of any of the five extant species of odd-toed ungulates in the family Rhinocerotidae, as well as any of the numerous extinct species therein. Two of the extant species are native to Africa, and three to Southern Asia. The term "rhinoceros" is often more broadly applied to now extinct species of the superfamily Rhinocerotoidea. -->
  <Rhinoceros.description>Un rhinocéros (du grec rhinokerōs "nez-cornes", de rhis "nez" et keras "corne"), communément abrégé en rhinocéros, est un membre de l'une des cinq espèces existantes d'ongulés à bouts pointus de la famille des Rhinocerotidae, ainsi que de l'une des nombreuses espèces éteintes de cette famille. Deux des espèces existantes sont originaires d'Afrique et trois d'Asie du Sud. Le terme "rhinocéros" s'applique souvent de manière plus large à des espèces aujourd'hui disparues de la superfamille des Rhinocerotoidea.</Rhinoceros.description>
  <!-- EN: seals -->
  <Seal.label>sceaux</Seal.label>
  <!-- EN: The earless seals, phocids or true seals are one of the three main groups of mammals within the seal lineage, Pinnipedia. All true seals are members of the family Phocidae. They are sometimes called crawling seals to distinguish them from the fur seals and sea lions of the family Otariidae. Seals live in the oceans of both hemispheres and, with the exception of the more tropical monk seals, are mostly confined to polar, subpolar, and temperate climates. The Baikal seal is the only species of exclusively freshwater seal. -->
  <Seal.description>Les phoques sans oreilles, phocidés ou vrais phoques, sont l'un des trois principaux groupes de mammifères de la lignée des phoques, Pinnipedia. Tous les phoques véritables sont membres de la famille des phocidés. Ils sont parfois appelés phoques rampants pour les distinguer des otaries à fourrure et des lions de mer de la famille des Otariidae. Les phoques vivent dans les océans des deux hémisphères et, à l'exception du phoque moine, plus tropical, ils sont principalement confinés aux climats polaires, subpolaires et tempérés. Le phoque du Baïkal est la seule espèce de phoque vivant exclusivement en eau douce.</Seal.description>
  <!-- EN: sheeps -->
  <Sheep.label>moutons</Sheep.label>
  <!-- EN: Sheep (Ovis aries) are quadrupedal, ruminant mammals typically kept as livestock. Like most ruminants, sheep are members of the order Artiodactyla, the even-toed ungulates. Although the name sheep applies to many species in the genus Ovis, in everyday usage it almost always refers to Ovis aries. Numbering a little over one billion, domestic sheep are also the most numerous species of sheep. An adult female is referred to as a ewe, an intact male as a ram, occasionally a tup, a castrated male as a wether, and a young sheep as a lamb. -->
  <Sheep.description>Les moutons (Ovis aries) sont des mammifères ruminants quadrupèdes qui servent généralement de bétail. Comme la plupart des ruminants, les moutons appartiennent à l'ordre des artiodactyles, les ongulés à doigts pairs. Bien que le nom de mouton s'applique à de nombreuses espèces du genre Ovis, dans l'usage courant, il fait presque toujours référence à Ovis aries. Avec un peu plus d'un milliard d'individus, le mouton domestique est l'espèce la plus nombreuse. Une femelle adulte est appelée "brebis", un mâle intact "bélier", parfois "tup", un mâle castré "mouflon" et un jeune mouton "agneau".</Sheep.description>
  <!-- EN: tanays -->
  <Tanay.label>tanays</Tanay.label>
  <!-- EN: Tanay are large herbivores engineered to produce large anmounts of neutroamine. -->
  <Tanay.description>Les Tanay sont de grands herbivores conçus pour produire de grandes quantités de neutroamine.</Tanay.description>
  <!-- EN: tapirs -->
  <Tapir.label>tapirs</Tapir.label>
  <!-- EN: A tapir is a large, herbivorous mammal, similar in shape to a pig, with a short, prehensile nose trunk. Tapirs inhabit jungle and forest regions of South America, Central America, and Southeast Asia. There are four widely recognized extant species of tapirs, all of the family Tapiridae and the genus Tapirus. They are the Brazilian tapir, the Malayan tapir, the Baird's tapir, and the mountain tapir. The four species that have been evaluated are all classified on the IUCN Red List as Endangered or Vulnerable. The tapirs have a number of extinct relatives in the superfamily Tapiroidea. The closest extant relatives of the tapirs are the other odd-toed ungulates, which include horses, donkeys, zebras and rhinoceroses. -->
  <Tapir.description>Un tapir est un grand mammifère herbivore, de la même forme qu'un cochon, doté d'une courte trompe préhensile. Les tapirs vivent dans les jungles et les forêts d'Amérique du Sud, d'Amérique centrale et d'Asie du Sud-Est. Il existe quatre espèces de tapirs largement reconnues, toutes de la famille des Tapiridae et du genre Tapirus. Il s'agit du tapir brésilien, du tapir malais, du tapir de Baird et du tapir de montagne. Les quatre espèces qui ont été évaluées sont toutes classées sur la liste rouge de l'UICN comme étant en danger ou vulnérables. Les tapirs ont un certain nombre de parents éteints dans la superfamille Tapiroidea. Les parents existants les plus proches des tapirs sont les autres ongulés à doigts impairs, qui comprennent les chevaux, les ânes, les zèbres et les rhinocéros.</Tapir.description>
  <!-- EN: tasmanian devils -->
  <TasmanianDevil.label>diables de tasmanie</TasmanianDevil.label>
  <!-- EN: The Tasmanian devil (Sarcophilus harrisii) is a carnivorous marsupial of the family Dasyuridae. Until recently, it was only found on the island state of Tasmania, but it has now been reintroduced to New South Wales, with a small breeding population. The size of a small dog, the Tasmanian devil became the largest carnivorous marsupial in the world, following the extinction of the thylacine in 1936. It is related to quolls, and distantly related to the thylacine. It is characterised by its stocky and muscular build, black fur, pungent odour, extremely loud and disturbing screech, keen sense of smell, and ferocity when feeding. The Tasmanian devil's large head and neck allow it to generate among the strongest bites per unit body mass of any extant predatory land mammal. It hunts prey and scavenges on carrion. -->
  <TasmanianDevil.description>Le diable de Tasmanie (Sarcophilus harrisii) est un marsupial carnivore de la famille des Dasyuridae. Jusqu'à récemment, on ne le trouvait que dans l'État insulaire de Tasmanie, mais il a été réintroduit en Nouvelle-Galles du Sud, avec une petite population reproductrice. De la taille d'un petit chien, le diable de Tasmanie est devenu le plus grand marsupial carnivore du monde, après l'extinction du thylacine en 1936. Il est apparenté aux quolls et, de loin, au thylacine. Il se caractérise par sa carrure trapue et musclée, sa fourrure noire, son odeur âcre, son cri extrêmement fort et dérangeant, son odorat très fin et sa férocité lorsqu'il se nourrit. La grande tête et le cou du diable de Tasmanie lui permettent de produire les morsures les plus puissantes par unité de masse corporelle de tous les mammifères terrestres prédateurs existants. Il chasse des proies et se nourrit de charognes.</TasmanianDevil.description>
  <!-- EN: thrumbos -->
  <Thrumbo.label>thrumbos</Thrumbo.label>
  <!-- EN: A gigantic, graceful creature of unknown origin. The thrumbo is gentle by nature, but extremely dangerous when enraged. While its long fur is exceptionally beautiful, its hide is also incredibly resistant to damage. Its razor-sharp horn fetches a huge price.\n\nLegends say that an old thrumbo is the wisest creature in the universe - it simply chooses not to speak. -->
  <Thrumbo.description>Une créature gigantesque et gracieuse d'origine inconnue. Le thrumbo est doux de nature, mais extrêmement dangereux lorsqu'il est enragé. Si sa longue fourrure est d'une beauté exceptionnelle, sa peau est aussi incroyablement résistante. Sa corne aiguisée comme un rasoir se vend très cher.

Les légendes disent qu'un vieux thrumbo est la créature la plus sage de l'univers - il choisit simplement de ne pas parler.</Thrumbo.description>
  <!-- EN: walruses -->
  <Walrus.label>morses</Walrus.label>
  <!-- EN: The walrus (Odobenus rosmarus) is a large flippered marine mammal with a discontinuous distribution about the North Pole in the Arctic Ocean and subarctic seas of the Northern Hemisphere. The walrus is the only living species in the family Odobenidae and genus Odobenus. This species is subdivided into two subspecies: the Atlantic walrus (O. r. rosmarus), which lives in the Atlantic Ocean, and the Pacific walrus (O. r. divergens), which lives in the Pacific Ocean. -->
  <Walrus.description>Le morse (Odobenus rosmarus) est un grand mammifère marin à nageoires dont la répartition est discontinue autour du pôle Nord, dans l'océan Arctique et les mers subarctiques de l'hémisphère Nord. Le morse est la seule espèce vivante de la famille des Odobenidae et du genre Odobenus. Cette espèce est subdivisée en deux sous-espèces : le morse de l'Atlantique (O. r. rosmarus), qui vit dans l'océan Atlantique, et le morse du Pacifique (O. r. divergens), qui vit dans l'océan Pacifique.</Walrus.description>
  <!-- EN: whales -->
  <Whale.label>baleines</Whale.label>
  <!-- EN: Whales are a widely distributed and diverse group of fully aquatic placental marine mammals. They are an informal grouping within the infraorder Cetacea, usually excluding dolphins and porpoises. Whales, dolphins and porpoises belong to the order Cetartiodactyla, which consists of even-toed ungulates. Their closest living relatives are the hippopotamuses, having diverged about 40 million years ago. The two parvorders of whales, baleen whales (Mysticeti) and toothed whales (Odontoceti), are thought to have split apart around 34 million years ago. Whales consist of eight extant families: Balaenopteridae (the rorquals), Balaenidae (right whales), Cetotheriidae (the pygmy right whale), Eschrichtiidae (the grey whale), Monodontidae (belugas and narwhals), Physeteridae (the sperm whale), Kogiidae (the dwarf and pygmy sperm whale), and Ziphiidae (the beaked whales). -->
  <Whale.description>Les baleines sont un groupe diversifié et largement distribué de mammifères marins placentaires entièrement aquatiques. Elles constituent un groupe informel au sein de l'infra-ordre des cétacés, excluant généralement les dauphins et les marsouins. Les baleines, les dauphins et les marsouins appartiennent à l'ordre des cétartiodactyles, qui comprend les ongulés à doigts pairs. Leurs plus proches parents vivants sont les hippopotames, qui ont divergé il y a environ 40 millions d'années. Les deux ordres de baleines, les baleines à fanons (Mysticeti) et les baleines à dents (Odontoceti), se seraient séparés il y a environ 34 millions d'années. Les baleines se composent de huit familles existantes : Balaenopteridae (les rorquals), Balaenidae (les baleines franches), Cetotheriidae (la baleine franche pygmée), Eschrichtiidae (la baleine grise), Monodontidae (les bélugas et les narvals), Physeteridae (le cachalot), Kogiidae (le cachalot nain et pygmée), et Ziphiidae (les baleines à bec).</Whale.description>
  <!-- EN: wombats -->
  <Wombat.label>wombats</Wombat.label>
  <!-- EN: Wombats are short-legged, muscular quadrupedal marsupials that are native to Australia. They are about 1 m (40 in) in length with small, stubby tails and weigh between 20 and 35 kg (44 and 77 lb). There are three extant species and they are all members of the family Vombatidae. They are adaptable and habitat tolerant, and are found in forested, mountainous, and heathland areas of southern and eastern Australia, including Tasmania, as well as an isolated patch of about 300 ha (740 acres) in Epping Forest National Park in central Queensland. -->
  <Wombat.description>Les wombats sont des marsupiaux quadrupèdes musclés aux pattes courtes, originaires d'Australie. Ils mesurent environ 1 m de long, ont une petite queue courte et pèsent entre 20 et 35 kg. Il existe trois espèces existantes, toutes membres de la famille des Vombatidae. On les trouve dans les forêts, les montagnes et les landes du sud et de l'est de l'Australie, y compris en Tasmanie, ainsi que dans une parcelle isolée d'environ 300 ha dans le parc national de la forêt d'Epping, dans le centre du Queensland.</Wombat.description>
  <!-- EN: zebras -->
  <Zebra.label>zèbres</Zebra.label>
  <!-- EN: Zebras (subgenus Hippotigris) are African equines with distinctive black-and-white striped coats. There are three extant species: the Grévy's zebra (Equus grevyi), plains zebra (E. quagga), and the mountain zebra (E. zebra). Zebras share the genus Equus with horses and asses, the three groups being the only living members of the family Equidae. Zebra stripes come in different patterns, unique to each individual. Several theories have been proposed for the function of these stripes, with most evidence supporting them as a form of protection from biting flies. Zebras inhabit eastern and southern Africa and can be found in a variety of habitats such as savannahs, grasslands, woodlands, shrublands, and mountainous areas. -->
  <Zebra.description>Les zèbres (sous-genre Hippotigris) sont des équidés africains au pelage rayé noir et blanc. Il en existe trois espèces : le zèbre de Grévy (Equus grevyi), le zèbre des plaines (E. quagga) et le zèbre des montagnes (E. zebra). Les zèbres partagent le genre Equus avec les chevaux et les ânes, les trois groupes étant les seuls membres vivants de la famille des équidés. Les rayures du zèbre se présentent sous différentes formes, propres à chaque individu. Plusieurs théories ont été proposées pour expliquer la fonction de ces rayures, la plupart d'entre elles soutenant qu'elles constituent une forme de protection contre les mouches piqueuses. Les zèbres vivent en Afrique de l'Est et du Sud et peuvent être trouvés dans une variété d'habitats tels que les savanes, les prairies, les forêts, les arbustes et les zones montagneuses.</Zebra.description>
</LanguageData>
