<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <!--The following translations were generated by https://www.deepl.com/-->
  <!-- EN: beaver -->
  <Beaver.label>castor</Beaver.label>
  <!-- EN: Beavers are large, semiaquatic rodents native to the temperate Northern Hemisphere. There are two extant species in the genus Castor, the North American beaver (Castor canadensis) and the Eurasian beaver (C. fiber). Beavers are the second-largest living rodents after the capybaras. They have stout bodies with large heads, long chisel-like incisors, brown or gray fur, hand-like front feet, webbed back feet and flat, scaly tails. The Eurasian beaver has a more elongated skull with a more triangular nasal bone opening, lighter fur color and a narrower tail. The animals can be found in a number of freshwater habitats, such as rivers, streams, lakes and ponds. They are herbivorous, consuming tree bark, aquatic plants, grasses and sedges. -->
  <Beaver.description>Les castors sont de grands rongeurs semi-aquatiques originaires de l'hémisphère nord tempéré. Il existe deux espèces du genre Castor, le castor d'Amérique du Nord (Castor canadensis) et le castor d'Eurasie (C. fiber). Les castors sont les plus grands rongeurs vivants après les capybaras. Ils ont un corps robuste avec une grosse tête, de longues incisives en forme de ciseau, une fourrure brune ou grise, des pattes avant en forme de main, des pattes arrière palmées et une queue plate et écailleuse. Le castor d'Eurasie a un crâne plus allongé avec une ouverture nasale plus triangulaire, une fourrure plus claire et une queue plus étroite. On trouve ces animaux dans un certain nombre d'habitats d'eau douce, tels que les rivières, les ruisseaux, les lacs et les étangs. Ils sont herbivores et consomment de l'écorce d'arbre, des plantes aquatiques, des herbes et des carex.</Beaver.description>
  <!-- EN: capybaras -->
  <Capybara.label>capybaras</Capybara.label>
  <!-- EN: The capybara (Hydrochoerus hydrochaeris) is a giant cavy rodent native to South America. It is the largest living rodent in the world. Also called capivara (in Brazil), capiguara (in Bolivia), chigüire, chigüiro, or fercho (in Colombia and Venezuela), carpincho (in Argentina, Paraguay and Uruguay) and ronsoco (in Peru), it is a member of the genus Hydrochoerus, of which the only other extant member is the lesser capybara (Hydrochoerus isthmius). Its close relatives include guinea pigs and rock cavies, and it is more distantly related to the agouti, the chinchilla, and the coypu. The capybara inhabits savannas and dense forests and lives near bodies of water. It is a highly social species and can be found in groups as large as 100 individuals, but usually lives in groups of 10–20 individuals. The capybara is not a threatened species, but it is hunted for its meat and hide and also for grease from its thick fatty skin. -->
  <Capybara.description>Le capybara (Hydrochoerus hydrochaeris) est un rongeur cavy géant originaire d'Amérique du Sud. C'est le plus grand rongeur vivant au monde. Également appelé capivara (au Brésil), capiguara (en Bolivie), chigüire, chigüiro, ou fercho (en Colombie et au Venezuela), carpincho (en Argentine, au Paraguay et en Uruguay) et ronsoco (au Pérou), il appartient au genre Hydrochoerus, dont le seul autre membre existant est le petit capybara (Hydrochoerus isthmius). Ses proches parents sont le cochon d'Inde et le cavie des rochers, et il est plus éloigné de l'agouti, du chinchilla et du ragondin. Le capybara habite les savanes et les forêts denses et vit près des plans d'eau. Il s'agit d'une espèce très sociale qui peut se trouver en groupes de 100 individus, mais qui vit généralement en groupes de 10 à 20 individus. Le capybara n'est pas une espèce menacée, mais il est chassé pour sa viande et sa peau, ainsi que pour la graisse de sa peau épaisse et grasse.</Capybara.description>
  <!-- EN: ferrets -->
  <Ferret.label>furets</Ferret.label>
  <!-- EN: The ferret (Mustela putorius furo) is the domesticated form of the European polecat, a mammal belonging to the same genus as the weasel, Mustela, in the family Mustelidae. Their fur is typically brown, black, white, or mixed. They have an average length of 51 cm (20 in), including a 13 cm (5.1 in) tail, weigh about between 0.7 and 2.0 kg (1.5 and 4.4 lb), and have a natural lifespan of 7 to 10 years. Ferrets are sexually dimorphic predators, with males being substantially larger than females. -->
  <Ferret.description>Le furet (Mustela putorius furo) est la forme domestiquée du putois européen, un mammifère appartenant au même genre que la belette, Mustela, dans la famille des Mustélidés. Sa fourrure est typiquement brune, noire, blanche ou mixte. Il mesure en moyenne 51 cm de long, dont 13 cm pour la queue, pèse entre 0,7 et 2,0 kg et a une espérance de vie naturelle de 7 à 10 ans. Les furets sont des prédateurs sexuellement dimorphiques, les mâles étant nettement plus grands que les femelles.</Ferret.description>
  <!-- EN: guinea pigs -->
  <GuineaPig.label>cochons d'Inde</GuineaPig.label>
  <!-- EN: Cavia is a genus in the subfamily Caviinae that contains the rodents commonly known as guinea pigs or cavies. The best-known species in this genus is the domestic guinea pig, Cavia porcellus, an important meat animal in South America and a common household pet outside South America. -->
  <GuineaPig.description>Cavia est un genre de la sous-famille des Caviinae qui contient les rongeurs communément appelés cochons d'Inde ou cavies. L'espèce la plus connue de ce genre est le cochon d'Inde domestique, Cavia porcellus, un important animal de boucherie en Amérique du Sud et un animal domestique courant en dehors de l'Amérique du Sud.</GuineaPig.description>
  <!-- EN: hares -->
  <Hare.label>lièvres</Hare.label>
  <!-- EN: Hares and jackrabbits are leporids belonging to the genus Lepus. Hares are classified in the same family as rabbits. They are similar in size and form to rabbits and have similar herbivorous diets, but generally have longer ears and live solitarily or in pairs. Also unlike rabbits, their young are able to fend for themselves shortly after birth rather than emerging blind and helpless. Most are fast runners. Hare species are native to Africa, Eurasia and North America. -->
  <Hare.description>Les lièvres et les lièvres variables sont des léporidés appartenant au genre Lepus. Les lièvres sont classés dans la même famille que les lapins. Ils ont la même taille et la même forme que les lapins et ont un régime alimentaire herbivore similaire, mais ils ont généralement des oreilles plus longues et vivent en solitaire ou en couple. Contrairement aux lapins, leurs petits sont capables de se débrouiller seuls peu après la naissance, au lieu d'être aveugles et sans défense. La plupart sont des coureurs rapides. Les espèces de lièvres sont originaires d'Afrique, d'Eurasie et d'Amérique du Nord.</Hare.description>
  <!-- EN: porcupines -->
  <Porcupine.label>porcs-épics</Porcupine.label>
  <!-- EN: Porcupines are large rodents with coats of sharp spines, or quills, that protect them against predators. The term covers two families of animals: the Old World porcupines of family Hystricidae, and the New World porcupines of family Erethizontidae. Both families belong to the infraorder Hystricognathi within the profoundly diverse order Rodentia and display superficially similar coats of quills: despite this, the two groups are distinct from each other and are not closely related to each other within the Hystricognathi. -->
  <Porcupine.description>Les porcs-épics sont de gros rongeurs dotés d'un pelage composé d'épines acérées, ou piquants, qui les protègent contre les prédateurs. Le terme recouvre deux familles d'animaux : les porcs-épics de l'Ancien Monde, de la famille des Hystricidae, et les porcs-épics du Nouveau Monde, de la famille des Erethizontidae. Les deux familles appartiennent à l'infra-ordre des Hystricognathi au sein de l'ordre profondément diversifié des Rodentia et présentent des piquants superficiellement similaires : malgré cela, les deux groupes sont distincts l'un de l'autre et ne sont pas étroitement apparentés au sein des Hystricognathi.</Porcupine.description>
  <!-- EN: rats -->
  <Rat.label>rats</Rat.label>
  <!-- EN: Rats are various medium-sized, long-tailed rodents. Species of rats are found throughout the order Rodentia, but stereotypical rats are found in the genus Rattus. Other rat genera include Neotoma (pack rats), Bandicota (bandicoot rats) and Dipodomys (kangaroo rats). -->
  <Rat.description>Les rats sont des rongeurs de taille moyenne à longue queue. On trouve des espèces de rats dans tout l'ordre des Rodentia, mais les rats stéréotypés appartiennent au genre Rattus. Les autres genres de rats incluent Neotoma (rats de meute), Bandicota (rats bandicots) et Dipodomys (rats kangourous).</Rat.description>
  <!-- EN: squirrels -->
  <Squirrel.label>écureuils</Squirrel.label>
  <!-- EN: Squirrels are members of the family Sciuridae, a family that includes small or medium-size rodents. The squirrel family includes tree squirrels, ground squirrels, chipmunks, marmots (including groundhogs), flying squirrels, and prairie dogs amongst other rodents. Squirrels are indigenous to the Americas, Eurasia, and Africa, and were introduced by humans to Australia. The earliest known fossilized squirrels date from the Eocene epoch, and among other living rodent families, the squirrels are most closely related to the mountain beaver and to the dormice. -->
  <Squirrel.description>Les écureuils sont des membres de la famille des sciuridés, une famille qui comprend des rongeurs de taille petite ou moyenne. La famille des écureuils comprend entre autres les écureuils arboricoles, les écureuils terrestres, les tamias, les marmottes (y compris les marmottes), les écureuils volants et les chiens de prairie. Les écureuils sont originaires des Amériques, d'Eurasie et d'Afrique, et ont été introduits par l'homme en Australie. Les premiers fossiles connus d'écureuils datent de l'époque éocène. Parmi les autres familles de rongeurs vivants, les écureuils sont les plus proches parents du castor de montagne et du loir.</Squirrel.description>
  <!-- EN: weasels -->
  <Weasel.label>belettes</Weasel.label>
  <!-- EN: A weasel /ˈwiːzəl/ is a mammal of the genus Mustela of the family Mustelidae. The genus Mustela includes the least weasels, polecats, stoats, ferrets and mink. Members of this genus are small, active predators, with long and slender bodies and short legs. The family Mustelidae, or mustelids, (which also includes badgers, otters, and wolverines) is often referred to as the "weasel family". In the UK, the term "weasel" usually refers to the smallest species, the least weasel (M. nivalis), the smallest carnivoran species. -->
  <Weasel.description>Une belette /ˈwiːzəl/ est un mammifère du genre Mustela de la famille des Mustélidés. Le genre Mustela comprend la belette, le putois, la fouine, le furet et le vison. Les membres de ce genre sont de petits prédateurs actifs, au corps long et mince et aux pattes courtes. La famille des mustélidés (qui comprend également les blaireaux, les loutres et les carcajous) est souvent appelée "famille des belettes". Au Royaume-Uni, le terme "belette" fait généralement référence à la plus petite espèce, la petite belette (M. nivalis), la plus petite espèce de carnivore.</Weasel.description>
</LanguageData>
