<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>
  <!-- Cat-like animals go into Felidae.xml -->
  <!-- Dog-like animals go into Canidae.xml -->
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Bear</defName>
    <label>bears</label>
    <description>Ursus is a genus in the family Ursidae (bears) that includes the widely distributed brown bear, the polar bear, the American black bear, and the Asian black bear. The name is derived from the Latin ursus, meaning bear.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <li>Bear_Grizzly</li>
      <li>Bear_Polar</li>
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Fisher</defName>
    <label>fishers</label>
    <description>The fisher (Pekania pennanti) is a small, carnivorous mammal native to North America. It is a member of the mustelid family (commonly referred to as the weasel family), and is in the monospecific genus Pekania. The fisher is closely related to, but larger than, the American marten (Martes americana). The fisher is a forest-dwelling creature whose range covers much of the boreal forest in Canada to the northern United States. Names derived from aboriginal languages include pekan, pequam, wejack, and woolang. It is sometimes misleadingly referred to as a fisher cat, although it is not a cat.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <!-- populated by ACP and Erin's critters -->
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Marten</defName>
    <label>martens</label>
    <description>The martens constitute the genus Martes within the subfamily Guloninae, in the family Mustelidae. They have bushy tails and large paws with partially retractile claws. The fur varies from yellowish to dark brown, depending on the species, and is valued by trappers for the fur trade. Martens are slender, agile animals, adapted to living in the taiga, and inhabit coniferous and northern deciduous forests across the Northern Hemisphere.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <!-- populated by Martens - Nature's Most Adorable Assassins -->
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Panda</defName>
    <label>pandas</label>
    <description>The giant panda (Ailuropoda melanoleuca), also known as the panda bear or simply the panda, is a bear native to south central China. It is characterised by large, black patches around its eyes, over the ears, and across its round body. The name "giant panda" is sometimes used to distinguish it from the red panda, a neighboring musteloid. Though it belongs to the order Carnivora, the giant panda is a folivore, with bamboo shoots and leaves making up more than 99% of its diet. Giant pandas in the wild will occasionally eat other grasses, wild tubers, or even meat in the form of birds, rodents, or carrion. In captivity, they may receive honey, eggs, fish, yams, shrub leaves, oranges, or bananas along with specially prepared food.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <!-- populated by ACP and Rainforest Mod -->
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Rat</defName>
    <label>rats</label>
    <description>Rats are various medium-sized, long-tailed rodents. Species of rats are found throughout the order Rodentia, but stereotypical rats are found in the genus Rattus. Other rat genera include Neotoma (pack rats), Bandicota (bandicoot rats) and Dipodomys (kangaroo rats).</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <li>Rat</li>
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Seal</defName>
    <label>seals</label>
    <description>The earless seals, phocids or true seals are one of the three main groups of mammals within the seal lineage, Pinnipedia. All true seals are members of the family Phocidae. They are sometimes called crawling seals to distinguish them from the fur seals and sea lions of the family Otariidae. Seals live in the oceans of both hemispheres and, with the exception of the more tropical monk seals, are mostly confined to polar, subpolar, and temperate climates. The Baikal seal is the only species of exclusively freshwater seal.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <!-- populated by VAE Ice Sheet and ACP -->
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Walrus</defName>
    <label>walruses</label>
    <description>The walrus (Odobenus rosmarus) is a large flippered marine mammal with a discontinuous distribution about the North Pole in the Arctic Ocean and subarctic seas of the Northern Hemisphere. The walrus is the only living species in the family Odobenidae and genus Odobenus. This species is subdivided into two subspecies: the Atlantic walrus (O. r. rosmarus), which lives in the Atlantic Ocean, and the Pacific walrus (O. r. divergens), which lives in the Pacific Ocean.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <!-- populated by VAE Ice Sheet and ACP -->
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
</Defs>
