<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Defs>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Dog</defName>
    <label>dogs</label>
    <description>The dog (Canis familiaris when considered a distinct species or Canis lupus familiaris when considered a subspecies of the wolf) is a member of the genus Canis (canines), which forms part of the wolf-like canids, and is the most widely abundant terrestrial carnivore. The dog and the extant gray wolf are sister taxa as modern wolves are not closely related to the wolves that were first domesticated, which implies that the direct ancestor of the dog is extinct. The dog was the first species to be domesticated, and has been selectively bred over millennia for various behaviors, sensory capabilities, and physical attributes.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <li>Husky</li>
      <li>LabradorRetriever</li>
      <li>YorkshireTerrier</li>
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Fox</defName>
    <label>foxes</label>
    <description>Vulpes is a genus of the Caninae. The members of this genus are colloquially referred to as true foxes, meaning they form a proper clade. The word "fox" occurs on the common names of species. True foxes are distinguished from members of the genus Canis, such as domesticated dogs, wolves, jackals and coyotes, by their smaller size (5–11 kg) and flatter skull. They have black, triangular markings between their eyes and nose, and the tip of their tail is often a different color from the rest of their pelt. The typical lifespan for this genus is between two and four years, but can reach up to a decade.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <li>Fox_Arctic</li>
      <li>Fox_Fennec</li>
      <li>Fox_Red</li>
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Warg</defName>
    <label>wargs</label>
    <description>The dire wolf (Canis dirus, "fearsome dog") is an extinct species of the genus Canis. It is one of the most famous prehistoric carnivores in North America, along with its extinct competitor, the sabre-toothed cat Smilodon fatalis. The dire wolf lived in the Americas during the Late Pleistocene and Early Holocene epochs (125,000–9,500 years ago). The species was named in 1858, four years after the first specimen had been found. Two subspecies are recognized: Canis dirus guildayi and Canis dirus dirus. The dire wolf probably evolved from Armbruster's wolf (Canis armbrusteri) in North America. The largest collection of its fossils has been obtained from the Rancho La Brea Tar Pits in Los Angeles.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <li>Warg</li>
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Wolf</defName>
    <label>wolves</label>
    <description>The wolf (Canis lupus), also known as the "gray wolf" or "grey wolf", is a large canine native to Eurasia and North America. It is the largest extant member of Canidae, males averaging 40 kg (88 lb) and females 37 kg (82 lb). On average, wolves measure 105–160 cm (41–63 in) in length and 80–85 cm (31–33 in) at shoulder height. The wolf is also distinguished from other Canis species by its less pointed ears and muzzle, as well as a shorter torso and a longer tail. The wolf is nonetheless related closely enough to smaller Canis species, such as the coyote and the golden jackal, to produce fertile hybrids with them. The banded fur of a wolf is usually mottled white, brown, gray, and black. Up to 38 subspecies of wolf have been recognized including the domestic dog.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
      <li>Wolf_Arctic</li>
      <li>Wolf_Timber</li>
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
  <Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
    <defName>Hyena</defName>
    <label>hyenas</label>
    <description>Hyenas, or hyaenas (from Ancient Greek ὕαινα, hýaina), are feliform carnivoran mammals of the family Hyaenidae. With only four extant species (in three genera), it is the fifth-smallest biological family in the Carnivora and one of the smallest in the class Mammalia. Despite their low diversity, hyenas are unique and vital components of most African ecosystems.</description>
    <pawnKinds>
    </pawnKinds>
  </Revolus.DogsMate.AnimalGroupDef>
</Defs>