<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <!--The following translations were generated by https://www.deepl.com/-->
  <!-- EN: dogs -->
  <Dog.label>собаки</Dog.label>
  <!-- EN: The dog (Canis familiaris when considered a distinct species or Canis lupus familiaris when considered a subspecies of the wolf) is a member of the genus Canis (canines), which forms part of the wolf-like canids, and is the most widely abundant terrestrial carnivore. The dog and the extant gray wolf are sister taxa as modern wolves are not closely related to the wolves that were first domesticated, which implies that the direct ancestor of the dog is extinct. The dog was the first species to be domesticated, and has been selectively bred over millennia for various behaviors, sensory capabilities, and physical attributes. -->
  <Dog.description>Собака (Canis familiaris, если рассматривать ее как отдельный вид, или Canis lupus familiaris, если рассматривать ее как подвид волка) - представитель рода Canis (клыки), входящего в отряд волкообразных канид, и является самым распространенным наземным хищником. Собака и современный серый волк являются родственными таксонами, поскольку современные волки не имеют близкого родства с волками, которые были впервые одомашнены, что подразумевает, что прямой предок собаки вымер. Собака была первым видом, который был одомашнен, и на протяжении тысячелетий ее селекционировали на различные формы поведения, сенсорные способности и физические качества.</Dog.description>
  <!-- EN: foxes -->
  <Fox.label>лисы</Fox.label>
  <!-- EN: Vulpes is a genus of the Caninae. The members of this genus are colloquially referred to as true foxes, meaning they form a proper clade. The word "fox" occurs on the common names of species. True foxes are distinguished from members of the genus Canis, such as domesticated dogs, wolves, jackals and coyotes, by their smaller size (5–11 kg) and flatter skull. They have black, triangular markings between their eyes and nose, and the tip of their tail is often a different color from the rest of their pelt. The typical lifespan for this genus is between two and four years, but can reach up to a decade. -->
  <Fox.description>Vulpes - это род из семейства собачьих (Caninae). Представителей этого рода в просторечии называют настоящими лисами, что означает, что они образуют соответствующий род. Слово "лиса" встречается в общих названиях видов. Настоящие лисы отличаются от представителей рода Canis, таких как домашние собаки, волки, шакалы и койоты, меньшим размером (5-11 кг) и более плоским черепом. У них черные треугольные отметины между глазами и носом, а кончик хвоста часто отличается по цвету от остальной части шкуры. Типичная продолжительность жизни представителей этого рода составляет от двух до четырех лет, но может достигать десяти лет.</Fox.description>
  <!-- EN: hyenas -->
  <Hyena.label>гиены</Hyena.label>
  <!-- EN: Hyenas, or hyaenas (from Ancient Greek ὕαινα, hýaina), are feliform carnivoran mammals of the family Hyaenidae. With only four extant species (in three genera), it is the fifth-smallest biological family in the Carnivora and one of the smallest in the class Mammalia. Despite their low diversity, hyenas are unique and vital components of most African ecosystems. -->
  <Hyena.description>Гиены, или гиены (от древнегреческого ὕαινα, hýaina), - это плотоядные млекопитающие семейства гиеновых (Hyaenidae). Это семейство, насчитывающее всего четыре вида (в трех родах), является пятым по численности биологическим семейством в отряде Carnivora и одним из самых маленьких в классе Mammalia. Несмотря на низкое разнообразие, гиены являются уникальными и жизненно важными компонентами большинства африканских экосистем.</Hyena.description>
  <!-- EN: tanukis -->
  <Tanuki.label>tanukis</Tanuki.label>
  <!-- EN: The Japanese raccoon dog (Nyctereutes procyonoides viverrinus), also known as the tanuki (Japanese: タヌキ or 狸; pronounced [taꜜnɯki]), is a subspecies of the Asian raccoon dog. Researchers have suggested that they be considered a separate species, N. viverrinus, or that raccoon dogs of Japan could be further divisible into separate subspecies as N. p. procyonoides (hondo-tanuki, ホンドタヌキ, 本土狸) and N. p. albus (ezo-tanuki, エゾタヌキ, 蝦夷狸), but both views are controversial. -->
  <Tanuki.description>Японская енотовидная собака (Nyctereutes procyonoides viverrinus), также известная как тануки (японский: タヌキ или 狸</Tanuki.description>
  <!-- EN: wargs -->
  <Warg.label>варги</Warg.label>
  <!-- EN: The dire wolf (Canis dirus, "fearsome dog") is an extinct species of the genus Canis. It is one of the most famous prehistoric carnivores in North America, along with its extinct competitor, the sabre-toothed cat Smilodon fatalis. The dire wolf lived in the Americas during the Late Pleistocene and Early Holocene epochs (125,000–9,500 years ago). The species was named in 1858, four years after the first specimen had been found. Two subspecies are recognized: Canis dirus guildayi and Canis dirus dirus. The dire wolf probably evolved from Armbruster's wolf (Canis armbrusteri) in North America. The largest collection of its fossils has been obtained from the Rancho La Brea Tar Pits in Los Angeles. -->
  <Warg.description>Суровый волк (Canis dirus, "страшная собака") - вымерший вид рода Canis. Это один из самых известных доисторических хищников Северной Америки, наряду с его вымершим конкурентом, саблезубым котом Smilodon fatalis. Суровый волк обитал на территории Северной и Южной Америки в эпоху позднего плейстоцена и раннего голоцена (125 000-9 500 лет назад). Название вида было дано в 1858 году, через четыре года после того, как был найден первый экземпляр. Признаны два подвида: Canis dirus guildayi и Canis dirus dirus. Вероятно, в Северной Америке от волка Армбрустера (Canis armbrusteri) произошел страшный волк. Самая большая коллекция окаменелостей этого вида была получена из смоляных ям Ранчо Ла Бреа в Лос-Анджелесе.</Warg.description>
  <!-- EN: wolves -->
  <Wolf.label>волки</Wolf.label>
  <!-- EN: The wolf (Canis lupus), also known as the "gray wolf" or "grey wolf", is a large canine native to Eurasia and North America. It is the largest extant member of Canidae, males averaging 40 kg (88 lb) and females 37 kg (82 lb). On average, wolves measure 105–160 cm (41–63 in) in length and 80–85 cm (31–33 in) at shoulder height. The wolf is also distinguished from other Canis species by its less pointed ears and muzzle, as well as a shorter torso and a longer tail. The wolf is nonetheless related closely enough to smaller Canis species, such as the coyote and the golden jackal, to produce fertile hybrids with them. The banded fur of a wolf is usually mottled white, brown, gray, and black. Up to 38 subspecies of wolf have been recognized including the domestic dog. -->
  <Wolf.description>Волк (Canis lupus), также известный как "серый волк" или "серый волк", - крупный собакообразный, обитающий в Евразии и Северной Америке. Это самый крупный из сохранившихся представителей семейства собачьих (Canidae), вес самцов составляет в среднем 40 кг (88 фунтов), а самок - 37 кг (82 фунта). В среднем волки достигают 105-160 см (41-63 дюйма) в длину и 80-85 см (31-33 дюйма) на высоте плеч. От других видов Canis волк отличается менее заостренными ушами и мордой, а также более коротким туловищем и длинным хвостом. Тем не менее волк достаточно тесно связан с более мелкими видами Canis, такими как койот и золотистый шакал, чтобы производить с ними плодовитые гибриды. Полосатый мех волка обычно пестрит белым, коричневым, серым и черным. Признано до 38 подвидов волка, включая домашнюю собаку.</Wolf.description>
</LanguageData>
