<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageData>
  <!--The following translations were generated by https://www.deepl.com/-->
  <!-- EN: beaver -->
  <Beaver.label>бобер</Beaver.label>
  <!-- EN: Beavers are large, semiaquatic rodents native to the temperate Northern Hemisphere. There are two extant species in the genus Castor, the North American beaver (Castor canadensis) and the Eurasian beaver (C. fiber). Beavers are the second-largest living rodents after the capybaras. They have stout bodies with large heads, long chisel-like incisors, brown or gray fur, hand-like front feet, webbed back feet and flat, scaly tails. The Eurasian beaver has a more elongated skull with a more triangular nasal bone opening, lighter fur color and a narrower tail. The animals can be found in a number of freshwater habitats, such as rivers, streams, lakes and ponds. They are herbivorous, consuming tree bark, aquatic plants, grasses and sedges. -->
  <Beaver.description>Бобры - крупные полуводные грызуны, обитающие в умеренных широтах Северного полушария. В роду Castor два вида: североамериканский бобр (Castor canadensis) и евразийский бобр (C. fiber). Бобры - вторые по величине из ныне живущих грызунов после капибар. У них крепкое тело с большой головой, длинные резцы, похожие на долото, коричневый или серый мех, похожие на руки передние лапы, перепончатые задние лапы и плоские, покрытые чешуей хвосты. У евразийского бобра более вытянутый череп с более треугольным отверстием носовой кости, более светлый цвет меха и более узкий хвост. Этих животных можно встретить во многих пресноводных местах обитания, таких как реки, ручьи, озера и пруды. Они травоядны, питаются корой деревьев, водными растениями, травами и осокой.</Beaver.description>
  <!-- EN: capybaras -->
  <Capybara.label>капибары</Capybara.label>
  <!-- EN: The capybara (Hydrochoerus hydrochaeris) is a giant cavy rodent native to South America. It is the largest living rodent in the world. Also called capivara (in Brazil), capiguara (in Bolivia), chigüire, chigüiro, or fercho (in Colombia and Venezuela), carpincho (in Argentina, Paraguay and Uruguay) and ronsoco (in Peru), it is a member of the genus Hydrochoerus, of which the only other extant member is the lesser capybara (Hydrochoerus isthmius). Its close relatives include guinea pigs and rock cavies, and it is more distantly related to the agouti, the chinchilla, and the coypu. The capybara inhabits savannas and dense forests and lives near bodies of water. It is a highly social species and can be found in groups as large as 100 individuals, but usually lives in groups of 10–20 individuals. The capybara is not a threatened species, but it is hunted for its meat and hide and also for grease from its thick fatty skin. -->
  <Capybara.description>Капибара (Hydrochoerus hydrochaeris) - гигантский волнистый грызун родом из Южной Америки. Это самый крупный из ныне живущих грызунов в мире. Также называемая капиварой (в Бразилии), капигуарой (в Боливии), чигуайре, чигуиро или ферчо (в Колумбии и Венесуэле), карпинчо (в Аргентине, Парагвае и Уругвае) и ронсоко (в Перу), она относится к роду Hydrochoerus, единственный сохранившийся представитель которого - малая капибара (Hydrochoerus isthmius). Близкими родственниками капибары являются морские свинки и скальные кави, а более отдаленными - агути, шиншилла и койпу. Капибара обитает в саваннах и густых лесах, живет вблизи водоемов. Это очень социальный вид, его можно встретить в группах до 100 особей, но обычно он живет группами по 10-20 особей. Капибара не относится к исчезающим видам, но на нее охотятся ради ее мяса и шкуры, а также ради жира из ее толстой жирной кожи.</Capybara.description>
  <!-- EN: ferrets -->
  <Ferret.label>хорьки</Ferret.label>
  <!-- EN: The ferret (Mustela putorius furo) is the domesticated form of the European polecat, a mammal belonging to the same genus as the weasel, Mustela, in the family Mustelidae. Their fur is typically brown, black, white, or mixed. They have an average length of 51 cm (20 in), including a 13 cm (5.1 in) tail, weigh about between 0.7 and 2.0 kg (1.5 and 4.4 lb), and have a natural lifespan of 7 to 10 years. Ferrets are sexually dimorphic predators, with males being substantially larger than females. -->
  <Ferret.description>Хорек (Mustela putorius furo) - это одомашненная форма европейского хорька, млекопитающего, принадлежащего к тому же роду, что и ласка, Mustela, в семействе Mustelidae. Их мех обычно коричневый, черный, белый или смешанный. Их средняя длина составляет 51 см (20 дюймов), включая хвост длиной 13 см (5,1 дюйма), вес - от 0,7 до 2,0 кг (1,5-4,4 фунта), а естественная продолжительность жизни - от 7 до 10 лет. Хорьки - хищники с половым диморфизмом, причем самцы значительно крупнее самок.</Ferret.description>
  <!-- EN: guinea pigs -->
  <GuineaPig.label>морские свинки</GuineaPig.label>
  <!-- EN: Cavia is a genus in the subfamily Caviinae that contains the rodents commonly known as guinea pigs or cavies. The best-known species in this genus is the domestic guinea pig, Cavia porcellus, an important meat animal in South America and a common household pet outside South America. -->
  <GuineaPig.description>Cavia - род в подсемействе Caviinae, содержащий грызунов, широко известных как морские свинки или кави. Самый известный вид этого рода - домашняя морская свинка, Cavia porcellus, важное мясное животное в Южной Америке и распространенное домашнее животное за пределами Южной Америки.</GuineaPig.description>
  <!-- EN: hares -->
  <Hare.label>зайцы</Hare.label>
  <!-- EN: Hares and jackrabbits are leporids belonging to the genus Lepus. Hares are classified in the same family as rabbits. They are similar in size and form to rabbits and have similar herbivorous diets, but generally have longer ears and live solitarily or in pairs. Also unlike rabbits, their young are able to fend for themselves shortly after birth rather than emerging blind and helpless. Most are fast runners. Hare species are native to Africa, Eurasia and North America. -->
  <Hare.description>Зайцы и джек-рабиты - это лепориды, принадлежащие к роду Lepus. Зайцы относятся к тому же семейству, что и кролики. По размеру и форме они похожи на кроликов и имеют схожий травоядный рацион, но, как правило, имеют более длинные уши и живут в одиночку или парами. Кроме того, в отличие от кроликов, их детеныши способны самостоятельно добывать себе пищу вскоре после рождения, а не появляются на свет слепыми и беспомощными. Большинство из них - быстрые бегуны. Зайцы обитают в Африке, Евразии и Северной Америке.</Hare.description>
  <!-- EN: porcupines -->
  <Porcupine.label>дикобразы</Porcupine.label>
  <!-- EN: Porcupines are large rodents with coats of sharp spines, or quills, that protect them against predators. The term covers two families of animals: the Old World porcupines of family Hystricidae, and the New World porcupines of family Erethizontidae. Both families belong to the infraorder Hystricognathi within the profoundly diverse order Rodentia and display superficially similar coats of quills: despite this, the two groups are distinct from each other and are not closely related to each other within the Hystricognathi. -->
  <Porcupine.description>Дикобразы - крупные грызуны с шерстью из острых шипов, или перьев, которые защищают их от хищников. Термин охватывает два семейства животных: дикобразов Старого Света из семейства Hystricidae и дикобразов Нового Света из семейства Erethizontidae. Оба семейства принадлежат к подотряду Hystricognathi внутри чрезвычайно разнообразного порядка Rodentia и демонстрируют внешне схожие перьевые покровы: несмотря на это, обе группы отличаются друг от друга и не являются близкими родственниками внутри Hystricognathi.</Porcupine.description>
  <!-- EN: rats -->
  <Rat.label>крысы</Rat.label>
  <!-- EN: Rats are various medium-sized, long-tailed rodents. Species of rats are found throughout the order Rodentia, but stereotypical rats are found in the genus Rattus. Other rat genera include Neotoma (pack rats), Bandicota (bandicoot rats) and Dipodomys (kangaroo rats). -->
  <Rat.description>Крысы - это различные длиннохвостые грызуны среднего размера. Виды крыс встречаются во всем порядке Rodentia, но стереотипные крысы встречаются в роде Rattus. Другие роды крыс включают Neotoma (стайные крысы), Bandicota (бандикотовые крысы) и Dipodomys (кенгуровые крысы).</Rat.description>
  <!-- EN: squirrels -->
  <Squirrel.label>белки</Squirrel.label>
  <!-- EN: Squirrels are members of the family Sciuridae, a family that includes small or medium-size rodents. The squirrel family includes tree squirrels, ground squirrels, chipmunks, marmots (including groundhogs), flying squirrels, and prairie dogs amongst other rodents. Squirrels are indigenous to the Americas, Eurasia, and Africa, and were introduced by humans to Australia. The earliest known fossilized squirrels date from the Eocene epoch, and among other living rodent families, the squirrels are most closely related to the mountain beaver and to the dormice. -->
  <Squirrel.description>Белки - это представители семейства Sciuridae, которое включает в себя мелких и средних грызунов. К семейству беличьих относятся белки-древоточцы, белки-землеройки, бурундуки, сурки (в том числе сурки), белки-летяги, прерийные собаки и другие грызуны. Белки обитают в Северной и Южной Америке, Евразии и Африке, а в Австралию были завезены человеком. Самые ранние окаменелости белок датируются эпохой эоцена, а среди других ныне живущих семейств грызунов белки наиболее близки к горному бобру и дремлющим мышам.</Squirrel.description>
  <!-- EN: weasels -->
  <Weasel.label>ласки</Weasel.label>
  <!-- EN: A weasel /ˈwiːzəl/ is a mammal of the genus Mustela of the family Mustelidae. The genus Mustela includes the least weasels, polecats, stoats, ferrets and mink. Members of this genus are small, active predators, with long and slender bodies and short legs. The family Mustelidae, or mustelids, (which also includes badgers, otters, and wolverines) is often referred to as the "weasel family". In the UK, the term "weasel" usually refers to the smallest species, the least weasel (M. nivalis), the smallest carnivoran species. -->
  <Weasel.description>Ласка /ˈwiːzəl/ - млекопитающее рода Mustela семейства Mustelidae. К роду Mustela относятся ласки, хорьки, горностаи, хорьки и норки. Представители этого рода - небольшие, активные хищники с длинным и стройным телом и короткими ногами. Семейство Mustelidae, или мустелиды, (в которое также входят барсуки, выдры и росомахи) часто называют "семейством ласок". В Великобритании термин "ласка" обычно относится к самому маленькому виду - малой ласке (M. nivalis), самому мелкому плотоядному виду.</Weasel.description>
</LanguageData>
